<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kamila reads</title>
    <description>I'm Kamila and I love books! If you looking for book recommendations you can check out my blog and see what I'm reading!</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 18:10:56 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 18:10:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Port of Shadows</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;‘Port of Shadows’ is the newest novel by Glen Cook from the Black Company universe. It is published almost twenty years after the original series. The story is taking place after events of the first anthology ‘The Chronicles of Black Company’. I was excited about this book because I quite enjoyed the original series.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In the beginning, it’s not clear what exactly this book is about. We have here three main plots: current situation, where the Black Company is station in a small town and not doing anything important; a story of a necromancer, whose greatest dream is to fully...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/portofshadows/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/portofshadows/</guid>
        
        <category>Port of Shadows</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Glen Cook</category>
        
        <category>The Black Company</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Na moment przed świtem</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;„Na moment przed świtem” to pierwszy tom nowego cyklu Magdaleny Wali „Za zakrętem”.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Jest to powieść obyczajowa, w której śledzimy losy dwóch kobiet, nieszczęśliwej Adrianny i Agnes, Ślązaczki w bardzo podeszłym wieku. Młodsza z kobiet tkwi w małżeństwie, gdzie traktowana jest jak niewolnica, gotowa na każde skinienie męża. Poznając jednak historię młodości Agnes, która przeżyła drugą wojnę światową, uświadamia sobie, że być może jej życie nie jest jeszcze zaprzepaszczone i podejmuje walkę o własne szczęście. Chociaż w tym celu będzie musiała zmierzyć się z bolesną przeszłością.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Książka jest lekka i czyta się ją bardzo szybko. Szczególnie podobały mi się fragmenty...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/namomentprzedswitem/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/namomentprzedswitem/</guid>
        
        <category>Na moment przed świtem</category>
        
        <category>Magdalena Wala</category>
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
        <category>Za zakrętem</category>
        
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Permanent Record</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Edward “Ed” Snowden is an American computer professional who worked for CIA and leaked classified data about mass surveillance programs to journalists, who then made them public. If you think about it, it sounds like a good story for a spy novel. But what it makes it more interesting, is that it really happened. In 2013 the news broke, and the world was shocked to discover that American government was collecting an enormous amount of data, all the emails, phone calls and text from a regular people all over the world. After six years of Snowden in ‘Permanent record’ shares...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/permanentrecord/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/permanentrecord/</guid>
        
        <category>Permanent Record</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Edward Snowden</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Szamanka od umarlaków</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;„Szamanka od Umarlaków” Martyny Raduchowskiej to pełna humoru opowieść o mrocznej tematyce. Ida Brzezińska pochodzi z wielkiego rodu czarodziejów, ale sama nie wykazuje za grosz zdolności magicznych. W ramach buntu postanawia uciec do Wrocławia na studia psychologiczne i rozpocząć wymarzone, samodzielne życie, wolne od zabobonów i przesądów. Okazuje się jednak, że nie będzie to takie proste, gdyż Ida zaczyna dostrzegać martwych ludzi wszędzie wokół siebie. A na domiar złego, oni wcale nie chcą zrozumieć, że ona może nie mieć ochoty z nimi rozmawiać. Na szczęście z pomocą przychodzi jej ekscentryczna ciotka Tekla, która przyjmuje ją pod swoje skrzydła.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ida, oprócz...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/szamanka/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/szamanka/</guid>
        
        <category>Szamanka od umarlaków</category>
        
        <category>Martyna Raduchowska</category>
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Angel Mage</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;‘Angel Mage’ is the newest fantasy novel by Garth Nix. It’s a stand-alone with a very original magic system based on summoning angels and using their powers. I was hooked from the very first pages.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Liliath was a very talented icon maker with extraordinary powers, but with a fall of her state and its archangel disappearance, she was forced to flee and run for her life. She goes into a magically induced sleep to wait for a convenient time to get back and restore the fallen angel to its glorious power. And make their enemies pay.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Four young people who...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/angelmage/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/angelmage/</guid>
        
        <category>Angel Mage</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Garth Nix</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lost and Found</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;‘Lost and Found’ is a new novel written by Orson Scott Card. Contrary to most of his book, this is not a sci-fi or fantasy story, but Young Adult contemporary with a little bit sparkle of everyday magic. I didn’t know what to expect of this book, but as I’m a big fan of the author himself, I had to check it out.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It’s a story about fourteen-year-old boy Ezekiel. He has an exceptional talent of finding lost things and instantly knowing where the owner is. It sounds good in theory, but it quickly turns up to get the boy...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/lostandfound/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/lostandfound/</guid>
        
        <category>Lost and Found</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Orson Scott Card</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Candidate</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;‘Candidate’ by Rachel E. Carter is the third book in ‘The Black Mage’ series, telling a story of Ryiah, a girl from a poor family who dreamed about becoming the legendary Black Mage. I was waiting impatiently for this volume because the ending of the previous one provided us for entirely new perspectives for unravelling this tale.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ryiah is twenty now, and she has already achieved so much it’s unbelievable. Thanks to her extremely hard work she became a black mage, she saved the kingdom from Caltoh’s sneaky attack and in the meantime, she managed to win prince’s heart and...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/candidate/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/candidate/</guid>
        
        <category>Candidate</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Rachel E. Carter</category>
        
        <category>The Black Mage</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Last Command</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;‘The Last Command’ is the last book in ‘Star Wars: The Thrawn Trilogy’ series by Timothy Zahn. It’s an explosive conclusion of the conflict between the New Republic and Imperium lead by Thrawn. Who will be the winner? Does Republic stand a chance against the military genius of the last Imperial Grand Admiral?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A lot is happening in the last book. Imperium is using their newly acquired ships populated with clone soldiers to breaking through New Republic’s defence and taking over planets from their jurisdiction. With their main advantage of more significant military resources gone, the former Rebels becomes desperate...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/thelastcommand/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thelastcommand/</guid>
        
        <category>The Last Command</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Timothy Zahn</category>
        
        <category>Star Wars The Thrawn Trilogy</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Empire of Silence</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;‘Empire of Silence’ by Christopher Ruocchio is the first book in new ‘Sun Eater’ sci-fi series. It was advertised as complex as ‘Dune’ and atmospheric as ‘The Shadow of the Wind’. I usually don’t like comparisons to other books on covers, but in this case, it was surprisingly accurate.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In the beginning, we met Hadrian Marlowe, who earned the reputation of a hero and a monster. Currently, he spends his days imprisoned and writing down his memories, since the very start, when he was just a young man, son of influential archon of prosperous planet Delos. Don’t expect any fireworks,...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/empireofsilence/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/empireofsilence/</guid>
        
        <category>Empire of Silence</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Christoper Ruocchio</category>
        
        <category>Sun Eater</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kolory zła. Czerwień</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Kolory zła. Czerwień” to najnowsza powieść kryminalna Małgorzaty Oliwii Sobczak. Akcja dzieje się w Sopocie i historię poznajemy dwutorowo, wydarzenia z lat 90ych przeplatają się z teraźniejszością. Na sopockiej plaży zostaje znalezione ciało młodej kobiety, okaleczone w pewien szczególny sposób. Do złudzenia przypomina to morderstwo sprzed 17 lat, którego sprawca nigdy nie został złapany. Czy to możliwe, że zbrodniarz ponownie ujawnił się po tak długim czasie? Czy może jest to sprawka naśladowcy? Leopold Bilski, młody prokurator wraz ze swymi współpracownikami postanawia za wszelką cenę znaleźć sprawcę wierząc, że jeśli rozwikła zagadkę z przeszłości, pomoże to również w aktualnym śledztwie.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Książkę...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/czerwien/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/czerwien/</guid>
        
        <category>Kolory zła. Czerwień</category>
        
        <category>Małgorzata Oliwia Sobczak</category>
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
        <category>Kryminał</category>
        
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dziecko Odyna</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;„Dziecko Odyna” autorstwa Siri Pettersen to pierwszy tom cyklu „Krucze Pierścienie”. Autorka zabiera nas w niesamowitą podróż do inspirowanego folklorem skandynawskim świata Ym, gdzie istnieje jedenaście krain a jego mieszkańcy, aetlingowie, wyglądają zupełnie jak ludzie, ale mają też ogony, z których są bardzo dumni oraz mogą korzystać z Evny, przepełniającej cały ich świat magii.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Hirka ma piętnaście lat i zawsze była traktowana jak odmieniec, gdyż sama nie posiada ogona. Zawsze wierzyła w historię, którą opowiadał jej ojciec, że odgryzły go wilki, gdy była niemowlęciem. Jednak wraz z nadciągającym Rytuałem, któremu poddają się wszyscy młodzi ludzi dziewczyna staje się coraz bardziej...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/dzieckoodyna/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/dzieckoodyna/</guid>
        
        <category>Dziecko Odyna</category>
        
        <category>Siri Pettersen</category>
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
        <category>Krucze Pierścienie</category>
        
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Crown Tower</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Crown Tower” by Michael J. Sullivan is the first book in “The Riyria Chronicles”. It is a sequel to “The Riyria Revelations” series (which was published first), and it tells the story of Hadrian and Royce from the very beginning. I like reading from the chronological order of the story, so I started with this one.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Hadrian Blackwater has nothing to fight for anymore. He was a soldier in different armies and killed loads of people across half of the world. But he is bone tired and fed up with this existence. When he receives a letter informing about...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/thecrowntower/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thecrowntower/</guid>
        
        <category>The Crown Tower</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Michael J. Sullivan</category>
        
        <category>The Riyria Chronicles</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kingdom of Souls</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;‘Kingdom of Souls’ is the first YA Fantasy novel by Rena Barron. And what a fantastic debut it is! I requested the ARC of this book from NetGalley because I was intrigued by a story about witchdoctor. That’s not a popular theme for fantasy books, it made this one stands out from the very beginning.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Arrah is born to a family of powerful witchdoctors. Her parents and her grandmother are the most magickly gifted people in all tribes. But so far, all she can do is seeing traces of magic in the air, but she can’t command it. And with...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/kingdomofsouls/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/kingdomofsouls/</guid>
        
        <category>Kingdom of Souls</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Rena Barron</category>
        
        <category>The Last Witchdoctor</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Gone World</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;‘The Gone World’ by Tom Sweterlitsch is a fusion of sci-fi and mystery novel. I’m personally a fan of both genres so I couldn’t wait to read it. The story began in 1997. Shannon Moss, who works for Naval Criminal Investigative Service, is given a case of former SEAL marine family murder. On the site, she also discovers that his teenage daughter went missing, and she is determined to find the girl alive. Everything gets more complicated, when it turns out, that missing SEAL was also participating in Deep Travel assignments, meaning he was travelling to the future. Shannon is...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/goneworld/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/goneworld/</guid>
        
        <category>The Gone World</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Tom Sweterlitsch</category>
        
        <category>Time Travel</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Empress Orchid</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Empress Orchid is a history-based novel written by Anchee Min. We learn about the life of Empress Dowager Cixi, her early life and how she came into the power in the Chinese government. It is an exciting story, considering the complicated political situation the country was after the Opium Wars. Young Orchid is desperate to escape an arranged marriage with her opium-addicted cousin volunteer to herself as a candidate for an imperial concubine. What seemed to be a long shot surprisingly pays out. She is not only approved as a worthy contender but also manage to catch the attention of...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/empressorchid/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/empressorchid/</guid>
        
        <category>Empress Orchid</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Anchee Min</category>
        
        <category>Historical Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We Hunt the Flame</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We Hunt the Flame is a debut novel by Hafsah Faizal, the first book in duology Sands of Arawiya. The action takes place in a fantasy world of Arawiya inspired by ancient Arabia. It’s an epic tale of adventure, searching for identity, standing up against injustice and fighting to bring the lost magic back to the troubled world. That said, I was expecting a thrilling and exotic story. Unfortunately, I was a bit disappointed.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Zafira is a fearless girl. Every day she put on a man’s clothes and brave the cursed forest to hunt for food to feed the people...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/wehunttheflame/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/wehunttheflame/</guid>
        
        <category>We Hunt the Flame</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Hafsah Faizal</category>
        
        <category>Young Adult</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Truth About Lies</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Would you like to have a photographic memory? All your brain would need is just one look to remember all the information from the viewed page. Or maybe you would like to go further, to remember everything, every little detail of your life, each conversation, every argument and all the sad things that ever happened to you? It doesn’t sound so appealing anymore, does it? But Jess Wilson must deal with it since she turned 11. How can you live your life, when your friend jumped from the window, and every time you close your eyes you can see her...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/thetruthaboutlies/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thetruthaboutlies/</guid>
        
        <category>The Truth About Lies</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Tracy Darnton</category>
        
        <category>Young Adult</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Supernova Era</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Supernova Era is a book from bestselling author Cixin Liu, author of award-winning The Three Bodies Problem novel. I’ve heard a lot about him and was very excited to read some of his work, although I must admit I was a bit scared of too much-complicated science in his book. But in the case of Supernova Era, it is no problem at all. There’s not much hard science here, it’s more like dystopian political fiction in fact. We have a dying star here, yes, but it’s only the beginning of the whole story.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Earth is showered by the deadly...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/supernovaera/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/supernovaera/</guid>
        
        <category>Supernova Era</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Cixin Liu</category>
        
        <category>dystopia</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Tiger Catcher</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Tiger Catcher written by Paullina Simons is the first book in End of Forever series. I’ve never read anything by this author before and I’m quite pleased with this one. It’s not a typical contemporary love story. It’s full of magic, faith and hope that true love never dies.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Julian Cruz is young and handsome so his life couldn’t be any better. That is true until he sees a pretty debutante on the stage, Josephine Collins. From the very first sight, Julian has no doubts that she is someone exceptional. When he meets her again sometime later by pure...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/tigercatcher/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/tigercatcher/</guid>
        
        <category>The Tiger Catcher</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Paullina Simons</category>
        
        <category>End of Forever</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Triskel. Gwardia</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Triskel Gwardia to debiut powieściowy Krystyny Chodorowskiej. Autorka ma na swoim koncie kilka opowiadań, z których jedno nominowane było do nagrody im. Janusza A. Zajdla. Ja niestety nie miałam okazji ich przeczytać, więc było to moje pierwsze spotkanie z autorką.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Książkę czyta się lekko i szybko. Główną bohaterką jest Sinead Clarke, która ma nadprzyrodzone moce i służy w Gwardii miasta Scyld City jako Mayday, etatowa superbohaterka. Poza tym studiuje i angażuje się społecznie pomagając imigrantom i uciekinierom ze swojego rodzimego kraju Sidheanii. Czytając książkę czuje się mocno komiksowy klimat rodem z Marvela, czy DC.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Trochę mi jednak w tej książce...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/triskel/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/triskel/</guid>
        
        <category>Triskel. Gwardia</category>
        
        <category>Krystyna Chodorowska</category>
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
        <category>superbohater</category>
        
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Twierdza Tytonu</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Twierdza Tytonu to drugi tom opowieści o Twierdzy Kimerydu i jej mieszkańcach. Tutaj akcja rozpoczyna się aż dziesięć lat po dramatycznym zakończeniu poprzedniej części. Do głosu dochodzi nowe pokolenie bohaterów, ale nie zabraknie również naszych ulubionych chłopców, którzy jednak zmuszeni zostają, by szybko wydorośleć. Tym razem większa część książki dzieje się w imperialnej Europie, poznajemy więc w końcu osławione Vintage i dwór Brytanika, o którym tyle było mowy w Twierdzy Kimerydu.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Książka objętościowo jest większa niż poprzednia część, jednak muszę przyznać, że czytało mi się ją lepiej. Nie wiem, czy to zasługa tego, że już weszłam w alternatywny świat Kimerydu,...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/twierdzatytonu/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/twierdzatytonu/</guid>
        
        <category>Twierdza Kimerydu</category>
        
        <category>Magdalena Pioruńska</category>
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
        <category>Twierdza Tytonu</category>
        
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Call of Earth</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Call of Earth is the second book in a Homecoming Saga by Orson Scott Card. The action takes place right after the ending of The Memory of Earth. After Gaballufix death, the city of Basilica is in chaos. Rasa is desperately trying to bring back peace to her beloved home, but even her extraordinary influence seems not to be enough. And while the city of women striving for survival, a powerful man will grab the opportunity and seize power in the vulnerable fortress. In the meantime, Nafai and his brothers will have to return one last time to Basilica...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/callofearth/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/callofearth/</guid>
        
        <category>The Call of Earth</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Orson Scott Card</category>
        
        <category>Homecoming Saga</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Time Bomb</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Time Bomb written by Joelle Charbonneau is a YA mystery/thriller. We have six young people with a different background who got stuck together at school when the bombs are detonated. To make a plot more captivating, on the first pages, we read that one of them has set up the explosives themselves.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The book is a short novel. Each chapter has about two to four pages, so you can read it quickly. And from the very beginning, you will be hooked. I really liked how the author a story with a chapter from POV each of the characters, and they...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/bomb/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/bomb/</guid>
        
        <category>Time Bomb</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Joelle Charbonneau</category>
        
        <category>YA!</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Shadow Frost</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Shadow Frost is a debut novel by young author Coco Ma. It’s the first book in a new fantasy YA series. It’s a story about Asterin, Princess of Axaria. There is a demon terrorising her kingdom, and it seems that she’s the only one who can defeat it. Together with her friends and elite guards, she’s embarking on a hunt. But none of them can predict the outcome of this journey.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This book is full of action, adventure and has an impressive magic system. There are nine elements that a person can wield, like water, air, ice, fire, and so...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/shadowfrost/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/shadowfrost/</guid>
        
        <category>Shadow Frost</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Coco Ma</category>
        
        <category>YA fantasy</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Twierdza Kimerydu</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Twierdza Kimerydu autorstwa Magdaleny Pioruńskiej to książka wielowymiarowa. Opowieść jest osadzona w alternatywnym świecie, który jednak bardzo przypomina nasz własny, w którym wiele rzeczy poszło bardzo nie tak. Mamy tu Cesarstwo Europejskie, którym niepodzielnie rządzi cesarz Brytanik, okrutny, przebiegły i bezwzględny człowiek, który nie zamierza z nikim dzielić się swoją władzą, a w imię postępu popełnia okrutne zbrodnie przeciw ludzkości. Jednak w Afryce Południowo-Wschodniej rdzenni mieszkańcy walczą z wpływami cesarstwa na ich życie. Potajemnie wciąż kultywują własną religię i obyczaje, a do ludzi z Europy podchodzą z dystansem i nieufnością. Taką ostoją, opierającą się propagandzie Cesarza, jest Twierdza Kimerydu, gdzie...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/twierdzakimerydu/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/twierdzakimerydu/</guid>
        
        <category>Twierdza Kimerydu</category>
        
        <category>Magdalena Pioruńska</category>
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
        <category>LGBT</category>
        
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Curse so Dark and Lonely</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A Curse so Dark and Lonely by Brigid Kemmerer is a modern retelling of Beauty and the Beast fairy tale for young adults. This was my favourite story when I was a kid, so I was very excited to read it!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Rhen is a cursed prince, and when I say cursed, I don’t mean he just looks ugly and reproachful. At the end of each season, he turns into a monster, he loses any awareness of who he is and surrenders to his animal instincts to kill whoever stands in his way. After that, the season resets and starts again...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/acursesodarkandlonely/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/acursesodarkandlonely/</guid>
        
        <category>A Curse so Dark and Lonely</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Brigid Kemmerer</category>
        
        <category>Beauty and the Beast</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Outcast</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Outcast written by Taran Matharu is a prequel to the very popular series Summoner. I haven’t read the main story yet, but because I like to read stories with chronological order, I decided that I want to read the Outcast first.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Arcturus is an orphan who is fighting for survival. But he has a grand plan. He collected enough money to run away from his slave-like job in the inn and maybe try his luck somewhere else now. But everything changes when he unintentionally steals a magic scroll from a noble boy, and it turns out he has the...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/theoutcast/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/theoutcast/</guid>
        
        <category>The Outcast</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Taran Matharu</category>
        
        <category>Summoner</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Shadow Run</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Shadow Run is the first book in Kaitan Chronicles series by AdriAnne Strickland and Michael Miller. It’s a YA adventure sci-fi based in the far future. The world is not only technologically advanced but has already faced the first drawback, when the vast Star Gates exploded for no apparent reason. This is the reason why the mysterious substance – Shadow is the main topic of speculation. It holds enormous potential to be used as fuel and supporting other technologies, but it’s also completely unstable. Most people can’t be near it for a long time. But there are some exceptions. Qole...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/shadowrun/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/shadowrun/</guid>
        
        <category>Shadow Run</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Adrianne Strickland, Michael Miller</category>
        
        <category>Kaitan Chronicles</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Zenith</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Zenith is a space opera written by Sasha Alsberg and Lindsay Cummings. The main character is Androma Racella, a powerful mercenary and space pirate with a very catchy nickname, Bloody Baroness. She’s a captain of spaceship Marauder, and together with her crew of equally dangerous girls, they are flying across Mirabel Galaxy in search of well-paid jobs. Everything changes when they got caught by a bounty hunter Dex and got a proposal they can’t refuse. They must embark on a mission no one else in the galaxy can fulfil.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Zenith is quite a big book which can be a little...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/zenith/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/zenith/</guid>
        
        <category>Zenith</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Sasha Alsberg</category>
        
        <category>Lindsay Cummings</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Siła Niższa</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Siła Niższa Marty Kisiel to kontynuacja Dożywocia, czyli dalsze losy naszych ulubieńców Licha i spółki. Po dramatycznym zakończeniu poprzedniej książki bohaterowie próbują się zaaklimatyzować w nowym domu. A nie jest to proste, gdyż wraz z powrotem do cywilizacji powróciły również rachunki do zapłacenia. Konrad wpada więc w szał pracy, przeplatanej gotowaniem dla całej rodziny (Krakers wciąż jeszcze nie powrócił) i napadami cholerycznej złości na wszystko co chodzi i Kica. Licho również nie może sobie poradzić z opuszczeniem Lichotki. Nawet nie ma ochoty sprzątać! A wszystko komplikuje się jeszcze bardziej, gdy do dożywotników dołącza kolejny anioł stróż Tsadkiel. I nie, nie...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/silanizsza/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/silanizsza/</guid>
        
        <category>Siła Niższa</category>
        
        <category>Marta Kisiel</category>
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
        <category>Uroboros</category>
        
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
