<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-07-15T14:51:43+01:00</updated><id>/</id><title type="html">Kamila reads</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><author><name>Kamila Komisarek</name></author><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Children of Blood and Bone by Tomi Adeyemi</title><link href="/cobab/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Children of Blood and Bone by Tomi Adeyemi" /><published>2018-07-13T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-07-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/cobab_en</id><content type="html" xml:base="/cobab/">&lt;p&gt;Children of Blood and Bone is a debut novel by Tomy Adeyemi. And what a great debut it is!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book takes us to the fantasy realm of Orïsha where all magic was eradicated eleven years ago and all who wielded it were slaughter. Their children live now as the lowest social beings, humiliated and despised. The protagonist Zélie is one of the repressed, she still remembers magic but have no hope of ever retrieving it. But everything change when the princess with a good heart decides it’s time to stop the tyranny of her father. Two young girls, unlikely friends, take up a journey to bring the magic back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story is progressing very quickly and it’s hard not to get into this magical world. So full of potential and yet restricted by humans fear and hatred. I really enjoyed how much the characters grow during this journey, especially princess Amari.
The narration is from first person and we can see the story through the eyes of Zélie, Amari and Inan - the king’s heir and captain of the royal guards, tasked with capturing his rogue sister and her accomplices. Thanks to that we can get to know the characters more deeply by seeing what is going through their heads. I’m not the biggest fun of the prince though. I don’t want to give away too many details but let’s say he can be really extreme with his actions and behaviours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Book was inspired by West African mythology so the whole magic system and the pantheon is very interesting and original. The maji (magic users in the book) were divided for ten different clans, each wielded different kind of magic. Additionally, all the spellworking was strictly connected to the gods who granted humans with the powers. Discovering this world was truly amazing!
The book also shows with great details a cruelty of racism and segregation and how little people need to overuse their power. Even though the action is based in a fictional world it’s not hard to see the similarities to our everyday life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book is an amazing and epic adventure. It has all the right ingredients for a great tale: protagonist with the destiny, the journey, magic and some surprising twists to give it a spice. And enormous wild cats used as horses. Because who wouldn’t want one of those, right? As I said before I’m not really convinced by Inan who often make me roll my eyes and sight heavily, but it was just a small part of the book. I do recommend it to all fantasy fans. And can’t wait for continuation!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4 stars/5&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kamila Komisarek</name></author><summary type="html">Children of Blood and Bone is a debut novel by Tomy Adeyemi. And what a great debut it is!</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Nevernight</title><link href="/nevernight/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nevernight" /><published>2018-07-11T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-07-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/nevernight_en</id><content type="html" xml:base="/nevernight/">&lt;p&gt;Nevernight written by Jay Kristoff is a book about young girl Mia, who lost her family very early due to unsuccesful revolution. Her father was hanged as a traitor, her mother and baby brother imprisoned and Mia herself bearly escaped her own death sentence. She sweared to avenge her family and make the opressors pay. To make sure she will succeed she wants to join the most deadly assassins guild in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story takes place in a fantastic world where the three suns shine bright and almost never set. It’s full of mythical creatures, deadly magic and hateful Gods. I really enjoyed discovering this world. Although I have a problem with the form the author choose to tell us more about it. We learn the most from annotations which are sometimes really long what I find very discracting. Fortunately as the action progress there is less of this notes.
The tale is full of action and quite captivating. Mia is a young lady driven by her desire to avenge her family. She’s also very unique, because she has a special friend in the shadows who helps her through her journey. We accompany her when she’s preparing to become the greatest assassin while discovering her own dark powers and limitations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was fascinated by the Red Church institution and their little community. It was exactly what you can expect from assassin’s school and then some more. There were some pretty drastic twists and surprises waiting for a reader along the way. I have a few moments, where I was completely taken off guard and had to take a deep breath before coming back to reading. The community itself was cruel, unforgiving and bold. But at the same time we could see that there were also the smallest kind feelings and gestures. You have to read it to find out if its possible to find friendship or love in such a place. Or maybe everything is only a game, a way to gain advantage over your compettitors?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall I did like the story. At first it was a little bit hard to get into it, because there’s a lot world specific terms and those annotations. But as the action progressed I felt more and more drawn to it. The world and its magic are fascinating, the characters interesting and multidimentional. If you like fantasy full of action and thrill you should definately read it. I most certainly read the next tomes soon!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kamila Komisarek</name></author><summary type="html">Nevernight written by Jay Kristoff is a book about young girl Mia, who lost her family very early due to unsuccesful revolution. Her father was hanged as a traitor, her mother and baby brother imprisoned and Mia herself bearly escaped her own death sentence. She sweared to avenge her family and make the opressors pay. To make sure she will succeed she wants to join the most deadly assassins guild in the world.</summary></entry></feed>
