<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kamila reads</title>
    <description>I'm Kamila and I love books! If you looking for book recommendations you can check out my blog and see what I'm reading!</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 09:19:51 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 09:19:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Splintered</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Splintered by A. G. Howard is a tale inspired by Alice’s Adventures in Wonderland. Alyssa Gardner seems to be a normal teenage girl. But nothing could be farther from the truth. Her mother was sent to mental hospital many years ago because of her delusions. Unfortunately, Alyssa discovers she can also hear flowers and bugs talking to her. It turns out it’s not an illness but a family curse, which has started when their ancestor, Alice, came back from Wonderland. Is it possible that Wonderland is real? And will Alyssa be brave enough to venture into unknown to break the...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/splintered/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/splintered/</guid>
        
        <category>Splintered</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>book recommendation</category>
        
        <category>A. G. Howard</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ana</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ana by Roberto Santiago is part contemporary and part crime story. Ana Tramel is a very talented lawyer, but many years ago she promised herself that she won’t go back to the court. Everything changes when unexpectedly she gets a call from her brother who, after years of silence, tells her that he is a main suspect in a murder case. It won’t be an easy case, because the victim is a manager of the casino, where Alejandro played poker and owes hundred thousands of euros. Ana sues the biggest gambling company in the country without any real assets or...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/ana/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/ana/</guid>
        
        <category>ana</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>book recommendation</category>
        
        <category>Roberto Santiago</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Shadow and Bone</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Shadow and Bone by Leigh Bardugo is the first book in The Grisha Trilogy. I’ve read Six of Crows duology by this author and completely fell in love with it, so I was very exited to read more stories from Grishaverse.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Our main character is Alina Starkov who is just another soldier, not very talented, certainly not very popular. She just want to get by, staying close to her only friend Mal, who is one of army’s best tracker. Everything changes, when they’re trying to cross the Shadow Fold, unnatural darkness crawling with monsters, which divides Ravka in half. They...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/shadowandbone/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/shadowandbone/</guid>
        
        <category>shadow and bone</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>book recommendation</category>
        
        <category>Leigh Bardugo</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Spektrum</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Spektrum by Martyna Raduchowska is the second book in the Black Lights series. Before I read the book I’ve heard it’s not typical continuation. It covers the same time period and events as first book. But this time the story is said from perspective of May the android.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Firstly I wasn’t thrilled with this idea, I wanted to know what happened next? But I actually liked this book more than the first one. I like Maya as protagonist, who despite her good intentions is called a traitor and have to flee to the Wall to save her life.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Since the...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/spektrum/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/spektrum/</guid>
        
        <category>spektrum</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>book recommendation</category>
        
        <category>Martyna Raduchowska</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stormdancer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Stormdancer by Jay Kristoff is a dystopian fantasy story based in Asian inspired isles of Shima. They are govern by cruel Shõgun who’s ruling with his whims and cooperate with mysterious Lotus Guild, who invented loads of useful machines and improvements but the lotus fuel they use is so toxic it’s killing the isles and its inhabitants.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Our protagonist is Yukiko, a young girl whom father is a hunter and a faithful servant of Shõgun. They are ordered to hunt a mythical Arashitora, a beast who was extinct for a long time. But they can’t refuse the order and so...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/stormdancer/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/stormdancer/</guid>
        
        <category>stormdancer</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>book recommendation</category>
        
        <category>Jay Kristoff</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Jinxed by Amy McCulloch</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Jinxed by Amy McCulloch is a light story full of humour and cute robotic pets. Lacey Chu is a teenager with a big dream, she want to work for Moncha Corp as companioneer - creator of smart, robotic pets (baku) who are also functioning as advanced smartphones. The first step is getting into prestigious school Profectus. It seems Lacy has done everything in her power to reach this goals, she worked hard and is really gifted in tinkering. But would it be enough, knowing her main competitor from school just happen to be the son of one of the most...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/jinxed/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/jinxed/</guid>
        
        <category>jinxed</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>book recommendation</category>
        
        <category>Amy McCulloch</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Throne of Glass by Sarah J Maas</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Throne of Glass by Sarah J Maas is the first book in the series about Celaena Sardonthien. After a year as a slave in a salt mines the assassin get an offer she can’t refuse: fight in a tournament to win a position of King’s Champion and after four years of servitude complete freedom.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The book is light and quick read. But again we have proud Celaena who, even after a year as a slave, is convinced she’s the best in everything and deserves all the respect and glory in the world. She simply couldn’t stand the fact that she...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/throneofglass/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/throneofglass/</guid>
        
        <category>Throne of Glass</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>book recommendation</category>
        
        <category>Sarah J Maas</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Cruel Prince by Holly Black</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Cruel Prince by Holly Black is a story about a girl who is forced to live among faeries in their magical kingdom. Sounds a bit familiar? Yes, I was sceptical and I wasn’t sure if I want to read it. I thought it was another version of ACOTAR and title indicating a romance theme. I couldn’t have been more wrong! I’m so glad I decided to read this book, because it is so much more!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Our main character is Jude, whose parents were murdered when she was a kid and she and her sisters are taken in by Fae...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/cruelprince/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/cruelprince/</guid>
        
        <category>the Cruel Prince</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>book recommendation</category>
        
        <category>Holly Black</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Metro 2034 by Dmitry Glukhovsky</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Metro 2034 written by Dmitry Glukhovsky is a post-apocalyptic tale about the people who survived the atomic war and now live trapped in Moscow subway system. The surface of the planet is polluted and now all kind of strange monsters are ruling there. It’s a sequel to a very popular Metro 2033, second book in a trilogy. I loved the first book, it was innovative and original, I was captivated by Artem’s story. Unfortunately the second book failed to impress me.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The story itself is less interesting then in a first book. Unexpectedly all contact is broken with the neighboured...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/metro2034/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/metro2034/</guid>
        
        <category>Metro 2034</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>book recommendation</category>
        
        <category>Dmitry Glukhovsky</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Lost Witch by Melvin Burgess</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Lost Witch written by Melvin Burgess is a story about witches set in the modern world. I was very excited for this book, because I find witches fascinating and was very curious what kind of tale the author will tell us. But I find this book very confusing.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Firstly, the cover, which is very beautiful, is very misleading (although this is publisher fault, the author said he didn’t like it either). It shows a young woman, when in fact the main character, Bea, is just thirteen years old when the book starts. It was very difficult for me to...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/thelostwitch/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thelostwitch/</guid>
        
        <category>The Lost Witch</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>book recommendation</category>
        
        <category>Melvin Burgess</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Assassin's Blade by Sarah J. Maas</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Assassin’s Blade by Sarah J. Maas is a book that contains five novellas about events that happened before the Throne of Glass series. I decided to read it first, because I like to read the story in chronological order.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I have to say it is a really good books. The fact that it is composed from a short novellas didn’t disturb receiving book as a whole story. We have a clear action flow from one tale to another. They were all action packed and interesting, so they got me really hooked. I wished I had time just to sit...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/assassinsblade/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/assassinsblade/</guid>
        
        <category>Sarah J. Maas</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>book recommendation</category>
        
        <category>the Assassin's Blade</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Renegades by Marissa Meyer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Renegades by Marissa Meyer is a story about people with extraordinary powers - heroes and villains. It sounded like my kind of book. I love all the comics and movies from Marvel and DC about superheroes! And I was curious about this author, as I haven’t read the Lunar Chronicles for which she is praised so much. So when a friend suggested me to read it I was on it!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;And then the reality came. This is a really big book. Hardback has about 550 pages (and I got myself a hardback because paperback was just plain ugly!). But...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/renegades/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/renegades/</guid>
        
        <category>superheroes</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>book recommendation</category>
        
        <category>the Renegades</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Łzy Mai by Martyna Raduchowska</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Łzy Mai by Martyna Raduchowska is a story based in cyberpunk reality. The action is taking place in the city of New Horizon, full of life and advanced technologies. We meet machines which took on all the easy, manual tasks done earlier by people. We also have androids, robots which look almost exactly the same as humans, while the latest ones fully embraced the bliss of advanced technology by using brain implants, cybernetic limbs or other upgrades. Sounds good? Yes, but all it’s not as wonderful as it may seems.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;From the very first pages of the book we are...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/lzymai/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/lzymai/</guid>
        
        <category>cyberpunk</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>book recommendation</category>
        
        <category>Łzy Mai</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Obsidio by Amie Kaufman and Jay Kristoff</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Obsidio by Amie Kaufman and Jeff Kristoff is the final book of the Illuminae Files trilogy. After first two books I was completely swept away and couldn’t believe how good they were. So the bar was set very high for it to deliver an equal satisfying ending to this epic space journey. Has it succeeded?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This part of the story is slightly different. We are again introduced with two more main characters (and lots of secondary ones) while the story is coming to an inevitable end. Because of that I feel like Asha and Rhys are my least favourite characters,...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/obsidio/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/obsidio/</guid>
        
        <category>sci-fi</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>book recommendation</category>
        
        <category>Obsidio</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Caraval by Stephanie Garber</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Caraval by Stephanie Garber is a book about two sisters who wanted to escape from their cruel father and to do that they throw themselves into mysterious and dangerous game of Caraval. They’ve heard the tales and legends about it and always dreamt of seeing it by their own eyes. And also, this year prize is one wish for the winner. What could go wrong?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I’ve heard a lot of good and bad opinions about this book. So of course I had to see by myself what all the discussion is about! I’m not regretting it. It reminds me a...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/caraval/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/caraval/</guid>
        
        <category>fantasy</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>book recommendation</category>
        
        <category>Caraval</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Court of Frost and Starlight by S. J. Maas</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A Court of Frost and Starlight is a short novella happening after ACOWAR. There is a lot of mixed feelings about this book. Some fans love it, as all S. J. Maas books, where others felt utterly disappointed with it. So let me say it: it is not a full part of the series as previous book. It’s more of few extra days with characters, kind of a gift for fans to not miss them too much while waiting for the next book. So I took this book with not too high expectations.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We meet our beloved characters a few...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/acofas/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/acofas/</guid>
        
        <category>fantasy</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>book recommendation</category>
        
        <category>ACOFAS</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Memory of Earth by Orson Scott Card</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Memory of Earth written by Orson Scott Card is a story that takes us millennia in the future on the distant planet Harmonia. The Oversoul, a super computer, was tasked to watch over it’s people and protect them - mostly from themselves. But after 40 millions years its system starting to fail and people get dangerously close to self-destruction once again.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We meet people of Basilica the society full of contradictions. They have some of very advance technologies, like levitating machines enabling disabled people to move freely, magnetic fields, databases and so on. And yet they are still very...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/memory/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/memory/</guid>
        
        <category>sci-fi</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>book recommendation</category>
        
        <category>Orson Scott Card</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>More Then a Game by Andrey Vasilyev</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;More Then a Game by Andrey Vasilyev is the first book in Fayroll series. It’s the literary genre called LitRPG short for Literary Role Playing Game which is basically combination of online gaming and fantasy/sci-fi fiction. It was my first opportunity to discover this genre (not counting Ready Player One) and a very pleasant one.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The main character Harriton Nikiforov is a journalist who has got a story to write about new, amazingly popular Virtual Gaming World of Fayroll. And it’s not just a normal computer game. He’d got some high tech equipment which enables him to immerse completely to...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/morethenagame/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/morethenagame/</guid>
        
        <category>LitRPG</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>book recommendation</category>
        
        <category>Fayroll</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Long War by Sir T. Pratchett and S. Baxter</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Long War is the second book in the series written by sir Terry Pratchett and Stephen Baxter. The story is based quite a few years after the first tome. Joshua is now a middle aged man and has his own family - wife and a son. Stepping is a new way of life and people are busy with colonizing countless of Long Earths.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It starts with a big stomp, the scene where we can see cruelty of humans experimenting on defenceless, kind-hearted trolls. And after that and the title I was expecting some great plot and terrible conflict tearing...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/thelongwar/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thelongwar/</guid>
        
        <category>sci-fi</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>book recommendation</category>
        
        <category>Pratchett Baxter</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gemina by Amie Kaufman and Jay Kristoff</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Gemina, the second book in Illuminae Files trilogy, was just WOW. I literary couldn’t put it down! This time action moves from fleeing fleet to jump station Heimdall, where our main characters are Hanna Donnelly and Niklas Malikov.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;At the beginning the book starts a little bit slow. We learn about the everyday life in the space station at the edge of the galaxy. We get to now Hanna, the daughter of the station commander with her rich girl problems and love life. We meet Niklas, her drug dealer, and small time criminal who fell in love with her completely...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/gemina/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/gemina/</guid>
        
        <category>sci-fi</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Jay Kristoff</category>
        
        <category>Amie Kaufman</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Children of Blood and Bone by Tomi Adeyemi</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Children of Blood and Bone is a debut novel by Tomy Adeyemi. And what a great debut it is!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The book takes us to the fantasy realm of Orïsha where all magic was eradicated eleven years ago and all who wielded it were slaughter. Their children live now as the lowest social beings, humiliated and despised. The protagonist Zélie is one of the repressed, she still remembers magic but have no hope of ever retrieving it. But everything change when the princess with a good heart decides it’s time to stop the tyranny of her father. Two young girls, unlikely...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/cobab/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/cobab/</guid>
        
        <category>fantasy</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>book recommendation</category>
        
        <category>Tomy Adeyemi</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nevernight</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Nevernight written by Jay Kristoff is a book about young girl Mia, who lost her family very early due to unsuccesful revolution. Her father was hanged as a traitor, her mother and baby brother imprisoned and Mia herself bearly escaped her own death sentence. She sweared to avenge her family and make the opressors pay. To make sure she will succeed she wants to join the most deadly assassins guild in the world.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The story takes place in a fantastic world where the three suns shine bright and almost never set. It’s full of mythical creatures, deadly magic and hateful...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/nevernight/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/nevernight/</guid>
        
        <category>fantasy</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>book recommendation</category>
        
        <category>Jay Kristoff</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
