<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kamila reads</title>
    <description>I'm Kamila and I love books! If you looking for book recommendations you can check out my blog and see what I'm reading!</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 11:34:34 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 11:34:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Outcast</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Outcast” by Louise Carey is the second book in the dystopian sci-fi thriller series “Inscape”. A story picks up a few months after the previous book’s ending. Despite all her hard work in bringing down the corrupted superior, Tanta is relegated to work amongst community guardians. But after an attack on InTech HQ, she is pulled back to the special forces unit to solve the case.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I loved the dystopian world the author created for her story. A few big corporations are the rulers, and you can either work for them or perish out in the wastelands without food, medicine,...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/outcast/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/outcast/</guid>
        
        <category>outcast</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Louise Carey</category>
        
        <category>inscape</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Between Two Worlds</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Between Two Worlds” is a debut historical fiction novel by Cheyenne van Langevelde. Enid, the daughter of the tribe’s chief, is captured by the Romans and shipped off to Rome as a slave. She will have to find a way to cope with her new, very different reality.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;From the beginning, we get the good feeling of being in ancient times, as the novel is skillfully written using archaic pronouns and other words we don’t use anymore. It does take some getting used to (at least for me, as I don’t read historical fiction often), but it certainly has its...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/betweentwoworlds/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/betweentwoworlds/</guid>
        
        <category>Between Two Worlds</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Cheyenne van Langevelde</category>
        
        <category>historical fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Town Called River</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“A Town Called River” by Igor Rendić is an urban fantasy novel with action set in Croatia and based on less popular Slavic mythology. It’s sort of The Witcher meeting friendly neighbourhood Spiderman in our modern world.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Paul is returning to Croatia after so many years that he hardly even speaks his native tongue. He wanted to wrap up everything quickly – listen to the testament of his late grandmother and deal with whatever she left behind – and then move on with his life. Unfortunately for him, Lena had particular plans for her favourite grandson. When Paul finally arrives...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/atowncalledriver/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/atowncalledriver/</guid>
        
        <category>A Town Called River</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Igor Rendić</category>
        
        <category>Urban Fantasy</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cytonic</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Cytonic” by Brandon Sanderson is the third book in YA Space Opera series “Skyward”. The review includes spoilers to the first two books, so if you haven’t read them yet, please skip it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The book starts with an immediate tense scene, where Spensa is trying to escape from Superiority’s soldiers chasing her. But instead of hyperjump straight home to Detritus, she chooses to venture into the nowhere to learn more about the delvers to gain an advantage in the upcoming conflict. In short, once again, we get a whole new world to discover.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I missed Spensa and M-Bot’s banter. It’s...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/cytonic/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/cytonic/</guid>
        
        <category>Cytonic</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Brandon Sanderson</category>
        
        <category>Skyward</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Empire of the Vampire</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Empire of the Vampire” by Jay Kristoff is the first book in the new series with the same title. The story is very dark and was meant to bring the image of vampires from the romanticised eternal creatures promoted by pop culture back to the bloodsucking monsters of legends from the olden days. And I say the author did a marvellous job.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;At the very start of the book, we meet Gabriel de León, the last Silversaint of a holy brotherhood imprisoned by his mortal enemies – the vampires. He is forced to tell his own story to the empress...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/eotv/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/eotv/</guid>
        
        <category>Empire of the Vampire</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Jay Kristoff</category>
        
        <category>dark fantasy</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Vow so Bold and Deadly</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“A Vow so Bold and Deadly” is the third and last book in the “Cursebreakers” series. I enjoyed the story so far, and I was curious how this tale would end. Word of advice before you read – this review will contain spoilers to previous books, so if you haven’t read them yet, I strongly recommend doing that before reading this review.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;“A Heart so Fierce and Broken” has left us in a very precarious situation. Syl Shallow, with Lia Mara as a new Queen and Grey at her side, gave Emberfall an ultimatum of sixty days to surrender before...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/avowsoboldanddeadly/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/avowsoboldanddeadly/</guid>
        
        <category>A Vow so Bold and Deadly</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Brigid Kemmerer</category>
        
        <category>Cursebreakers</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nemesis Games</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Nemesis Games” is the fifth book in “The Expanse” series by James S. A. Corey. And what a book! I think it was one of my favourites so far.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;First, we have chapters from the points of view of all Rocinante crew members, whom I adore, as they highlight the whole series. When they finally reach Tycho station after New Earth, poor Rocinante is wrecked, and the repairs will take good few months. Using the downtime, the crew decides to take care of their personal matters. Funnily enough, all at once, they leave poor Holden alone, setting off in different...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/nemesisgames/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/nemesisgames/</guid>
        
        <category>Nemesis Games</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>James S. A. Corey</category>
        
        <category>The Expanse</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sundered Souls</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;S”undered Souls” is the second book in the Viking inspired epic fantasy series “The Brotherhood of the Eagle” by Tim Hardie. I was lucky enough to receive the ARC from the author and was excited to continue the story of Rothgar and his companions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Unlike “Hall of Bones”, the sequel starts with a lot more tension. The Vorund Clan has seized control of most land in Laskar, crushing all those who refused to bend the knee for self-proclaimed King of the North, Adalrkir Asmarrson. Rothgar joined Johan Jokellsward, and with their newly formed Brotherhood of the Eagle, they fight against...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/sunderedsouls/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sunderedsouls/</guid>
        
        <category>Sundered Souls</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Tim Hardie</category>
        
        <category>The Brotherhood of the Eagle</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Look of a King</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Look of a King” by Tom Dumbrell is the first book in a medieval-inspired series “Pillars of Piece”. The story is based in an original world where four nations are occupying the main continent. They all live in peace since the treaty was signed eight years before, but unfortunately, harmony will not last much longer, and violence will once again spread through the land.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The tale follows two young men, Augustus, a pampered heir to the throne, who is a selfish prick, and Cyrus, an orphan living in the small village who love telling stories of bravery and chivalry....</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/loak/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/loak/</guid>
        
        <category>The Look of a King</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Tom Dumbrell</category>
        
        <category>Pillars of Peace</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cibola Burn</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Cibola Burn” is the fourth book in the explosive space opera series “The Expanse”. As soon as the intergalactic gate has been open, adventurous settlers move on to brave the unknown and colonise promising new planets. One of such planets is Ilus (or New Terra, depending on who you ask). The Belter’s ship managed to reach it first, and they started building their settlement right away. Even if the planet is similar to Earth, it is still a strange place, and living there is complicated. Things start looking up when the Belters discover a rich deposit of valuable ore. If...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/cibolaburn/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/cibolaburn/</guid>
        
        <category>Cibola Burn</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>James S. A. Corey</category>
        
        <category>The Expanse</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Death's Kiss</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Death’s Kiss” by Joshua Reynolds is the second book in “A Daidoji Shin Mystery” series based in the world from “Legend of the Five Rings”. I enjoyed the first novel in the series and was waiting eagerly to meet with a witty Crane again.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The story starts a few months after the conclusion of the investigation from “Poison River”. Shin is busy rebuilding the Foxfire Theatre, but deep down, he is already bored with his newest undertaking. When a friend from the Unicorn Clan asks him for a favour, he is more than happy to travel into a distant city...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/deathskiss/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/deathskiss/</guid>
        
        <category>Death's Kiss</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>A Daidoji Shin Mystery</category>
        
        <category>Legend of the Five Rings</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Blacktongue Thief</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Blacktongue Thief” by Christopher Buehlman is the author’s debut in the fantasy genre (most published books were horrors). I absolutely adore the cover, so I was thrilled when Gollancz asked me if I would be interested in Blog Tour with this book.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The novel is rather peculiar. After the first few chapters, I was somewhat appalled. The protagonist, Kinch Na Shannack, is a thief from the Takers Guild, and he is also the one that tells us the story. To say he’s unrefined is an understatement. From the beginning, we are bombarded by crude fart jokes and metaphors straight...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/theblacktonguethief/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/theblacktonguethief/</guid>
        
        <category>The Blacktongue Thief</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Christopher Buehlman</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Broken God</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Broken God” is the third book of “The Black Iron Legacy” fantasy series by Gareth Ryder-Hanrahan. This review will contain spoilers to the first two books because I can’t write anything of essence without it, so if you haven’t started this series yet, I advise you to go and read my review of “The Gutter Prayer” first, and then decide if you want to read it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Every book in “The Black Iron Legacy” has a different central theme. “The Gutter Prayer” mainly evolved around a heist and took place in Guerdon, with only minor mentions of what is happening...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/thebrokengod/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thebrokengod/</guid>
        
        <category>The Broken God</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Gareth Ryder-Hanrahan</category>
        
        <category>The Black Iron Legacy</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Marion Lane and the Midnight Murder</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Marion Lane and the Midnight Murder” is a debut novel by T. A. Willberg. It’s a mystery set in 1958 London, but with a bit of a fantasy twist. I absolutely adore the cover, which was the main reason I wanted to read this book.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I love the setting the author created. Marion Lane is an inconspicuous young woman who works in a tiny bookstore called Miss Brickett’s Secondhand Books and Curiosities. But the truth is, that’s only the cover-up for the secret organisation of private investigators, who are helping Londoners with cases, which police cannot or don’t want to...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/marionlane/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/marionlane/</guid>
        
        <category>Marion Lane and the Midnight Murder</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>T. A. Willberg</category>
        
        <category>Marion Lane</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Blade Itself</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Blade Itself” by Joe Abercrombie is the first book in “The First Law” trilogy. We follow the stories of three protagonists, barbarian Logan Ninefingers, nobleman Captain Jezal dan Lutar and Inquisitor Glokta.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The most exciting thing in the book is the characters. All of them should not be very likeable – an infamous barbarian who slaughter countless people, a selfish prick of a nobleman, and a ruthless torturer who hates everyone. And yet, it’s not all they are. The author creates his characters brilliantly, giving them so many different dimensions that we can’t help but be drawn by their...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/thebladeitself/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thebladeitself/</guid>
        
        <category>The Blade Itself</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Joe Abercrombie</category>
        
        <category>The First Law</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Shadow of the Gods</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Shadow of the Gods” by John Gwynne is the first book in a new epic fantasy series, “The Bloodsworn Saga”. If you love Vikings and Norse mythology, it’s a must-read!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The story follows three protagonists: Orka, ex-military living peacefully with her family on the outskirts of civilised lands; Varg No-Sense (absolutely love the nickname!), a former thrall (slave) on a quest for vengeance and last, but not least, Elvar, a brave young woman who decided she will be the only master of her destiny and forge her battle-fame. All of them starts with their separate routes, but very quickly,...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/theshadowofthegods/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/theshadowofthegods/</guid>
        
        <category>The Shadow of the Gods</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>John Gwynne</category>
        
        <category>The Bloodsworn Saga</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Architekci Czyściciele Materii</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Architekci Czyściciele Materii” to psychodeliczny thriller/kryminał z elementami fantastyki autorstwa Kamila Hajduka. Już z opisu widać, że nie jest to książka sztampowa i łatwa do zaszufladkowania gatunkowo. Jest to drugi tom cyklu „Architekci”, jednak autor zapewnia, że znajomość pierwszego tomu nie jest warunkiem koniecznym.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Sam pomysł na wykreowanie świata bardzo mi się podobał. Mamy tutaj Warszawę w klimacie nieco apokaliptycznym – komunikacja miejska (metro) jest wyłączone z ruchu, metropolią wstrząsają trzęsienia ziemi i inne niewyjaśnione zjawiska a ulice świecą pustkami wzmagając poczucie grozy i niepewności. Otóż stolica stała się podwórkiem dla potężnego Architekta, Tadeusza, który gardząc zwykłymi ludźmi, postanowił przejąć...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/architekci/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/architekci/</guid>
        
        <category>Architekci</category>
        
        <category>Kamil Hajduk</category>
        
        <category>Programistapogodzinach</category>
        
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mirrorland</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Mirrorland” by Carole Johnstone is a dark and twisty thriller. Cat lives in Los Angeles since she left her twin sister El over a decade ago, not making any attempts to contact her only family or mend the broken relationship. But when El disappears on her sailboat one day, Cat is forced to go back to Edinburgh and finally face her past.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;When I first started reading “Mirrorland”, I didn’t think I would like it. For one-third of the book, not much is happening. The author beautifully describes the haunting house where Cat spent her childhood. The building is full...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/mirrorland/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/mirrorland/</guid>
        
        <category>Mirrorland</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Carole Johnstone</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kości Skryby</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Kości Skryby” to drugi tom serii “Alcatraz kontra Bibliotekarze” autorstwa Brandona Sandersona. I chociaż cykl kierowany jest głównie do młodzieży, to ja osobiście go uwielbiam. Jest lekki, zabawny i zawsze sięgam po niego, kiedy potrzebuję czegoś na poprawę humoru.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;W tej części Alcatraz udaje się śladami Dziadka Smedrego (który znów się spóźnił) do tajemniczej Biblioteki Aleksandryjskiej. To jedno z najniebezpieczniejszych miejsc na ziemi, a sprawujący w niej władzę Bibliotekarze to nie zwyczajne wredne typy z pistoletami, jakich poznaliśmy w poprzedniej książce. O nie, Kuratorzy są dużo bardziej podstępni i niebezpieczni. Czy wspominałam już, że są nieumarłymi i mogę wyssać Waszą...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/scrivenersbnes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/scrivenersbnes/</guid>
        
        <category>Kości Skryby</category>
        
        <category>Brandon Sanderson</category>
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
        <category>Alcatraz kontra Bibliotekarze</category>
        
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Scrivener’s Bones</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Scrivener’s Bones” is the second book in “Alcatraz vs the Evil Librarians” series by Brandon Sanderson. Those books were written with Middle Graders as the primary target, but I love them none the less. They are light, funny, and entertaining, so I like to read them when I want an instant pick-me-up.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In the second book, Alcatraz must follow Grandpa Smedry (who was late. Again) to a mysterious Library of Alexandria. It’s one of the most dangerous places in the world, as the librarians in charge are not the regular, ordinary mean people with guns we’ve met in the...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/scrivenersbones/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/scrivenersbones/</guid>
        
        <category>The Scrivener’s Bones</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Brandon Sanderson</category>
        
        <category>Alcatraz versus the Evil Librarians</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Snapshot</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Snapshot” by Brandon Sanderson is a short detective/sci-fi story. Anthony Davis is a cop assigned to the Snapshot Duty.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is another fantastic idea of the author. In the near future, people came up with a way to recreate the specific day in time for the whole city. Police use this for their investigations – to track down the criminals, finding additional clues and so on. The protagonist and his partner are tasked with a simple case, one of their regular duties, but Davis is not satisfied. He saw traces of serious investigation he wasn’t told about, and he decided...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/snapshot/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/snapshot/</guid>
        
        <category>Snapshot</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Brandon Sanderson</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hall of Bones</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Hall of Bones” by Tim Hardie is a debut epic fantasy novel and the first book in the series “The Brotherhood of the Eagle”. I received a copy of the text from the author in exchange for an honest review. I have to say I was a bit weary, as, with debut books, it’s often hit-or-miss. But I liked the synopsis and felt like reading some epic fantasy in a Viking setting, so I gave it a shot. And I have to say I was positively surprised. If I didn’t know any better, I would never guess it was the...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/hallofbones/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/hallofbones/</guid>
        
        <category>Hall of Bones</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Tim Hardie</category>
        
        <category>The Brotherhood of the Eagle</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Abaddon's Gate</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Abaddon’s Gate” is the third book in “The Expanse” series. After the alien artefact builds the massive structure near Uranus, all the factions – Earth, Mars and the Asteroid Belt sent their envoys there, though no one is sure what to do with the strange Gate. Of course, Holden and his crew also find themselves on the way there. But the captain on the Rocinante doesn’t know yet, that someone is plotting to destroy him mercilessly.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For me, this book was not as good as the first two volumes. We have all new characters here: Melba, Bull and Anna, and...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/abaddonsgate/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/abaddonsgate/</guid>
        
        <category>Abaddon's Gate</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>James S. A. Corey</category>
        
        <category>The Expanse</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wezwij Sokoła</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Wezwij Sokoła” to pierwszy tom nowego cyklu “Śniący” autorstwa Maggie Stiefvater. Autorka znana jest przede wszystkim z serii o Kruczych Chłopcach i nowa książka jest poniekąd jej kontynuacją. Tym razem będziemy śledzić losy Ronana Lyncha i jego braci. Żeby sięgnąć po cykl “Śniący” nie jest konieczna znajomość poprzednich książek autorki, gdyż przeszłość Ronana jest tu wspomniana mimochodem, jednak dla fanów Kruczych Chłopców kolejne przygody jednego z bohaterów będą na pewno nie lada gratką.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;“Wezwij Sokoła” skupia się głównie na śniących i ich mocach. Sam pomysł bardzo mi się podobał, Ronan jako całkiem nieźle wyszkolony śniący potrafi zmaterializować w rzeczywistym świecie...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/wezwijsokola/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/wezwijsokola/</guid>
        
        <category>Wezwij Sokoła</category>
        
        <category>Maggie Stiefvater</category>
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
        <category>Śniący</category>
        
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Zodiaki. Genokracja</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Zodiaki. Genokracja” autorstwa Magdaleny Kucenty to powieść w klimacie biopunku. Świat został na zawsze odmieniony po wybuchu zarazy zwanej Pandorą, ludzie cierpią na niekontrolowane mutacje, środowisko zostało zanieczyszczone na tyle, że powstały miasta kryjące się pod ochronnymi kopułami. Społeczeństwo, które wyewoluowało z gruzów znanej nam cywilizacji jest zupełnie nowym gatunkiem.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Świat stworzony przez autorkę jest naprawdę bogaty i różnorodny. Czytając książkę od razu można zauważyć, że to, co widzimy śledząc losy bohaterów to tylko wierzchołek góry lodowej, a reszta wciąż czeka na odkrycie. Tytułowe Zodiaki zostały powołane do życia w laboratorium, ku szczytnemu celowi nieustannego udoskonalania rasy ludzkiej. Jednak jak...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/zodiaki/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/zodiaki/</guid>
        
        <category>Zodiaki. Genokracja</category>
        
        <category>Magdalena Kucenty</category>
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Poppy War</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Poppy War” by R. F. Kuang is a fantasy novel based on modern China history. Rin is a war orphan raised by the smugglers in poor Rooster province in the south, rural part of the Empire. To escape the arranged marriage, she put everything in preparing herself for the Keju – the exam that allows all those who pass attend the Academies. Thanks to her dedication and strong will, she is given a life-changing opportunity.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;“The Poppy War” is a long and complex story. It’s starting with a well-known trope. A poor orphan girl is attending an elite school,...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/thepoppywar/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thepoppywar/</guid>
        
        <category>The Poppy War</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>R. F. Kuang</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Siege and Storm</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Siege and Storm” is the second book in the “Shadow and Bone Trilogy” by Leigh Bardugo. I’ve read the first one more than a year ago, and somehow never got time to continue the series. Still, with upcoming TV series, I decided it’s high time to finish it mainly because I’m a devoted fan of “Six of Crows” duology.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I enjoy getting into the Grishaverse – the world that the author created. And I love that she called the genre tsarpunk – a mixture of high fantasy, 19th-century Russian culture and steampunk. I find it entirely accurate. This unique setting...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/siegeandstorm/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/siegeandstorm/</guid>
        
        <category>Siege and Storm</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Leigh Bardugo</category>
        
        <category>Grishaverse</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Night Parade of 100 Demons</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Night Parade of 100 Demons” by Marie Brennan is a fantasy novel based in Rokugan, the world from Legend of the Five Rings universe. It is firmly based on a feudal Japan, but also includes elements of other Asian cultures as well as magic.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Dragon Clan’s samurai, Agasha no Isao Ryotora, travels to help the remote village deep in the mountains. During the full moon, horrifying creatures of all kinds are attacking the settlement wreaking havoc wherever they go. He finds the situation is far worse than he expected and is also surprised to see another samurai already on...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/thenightparade/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thenightparade/</guid>
        
        <category>The Night Parade of 100 Demons</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Marie Brennan</category>
        
        <category>Legend of the Five Rings</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dywan z wkładką</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Dywan z wkładką” to komedia kryminalna autorstwa Marty Kisiel. Ałtorka przyzwyczaiła nas do książek pełnych elementów fantastycznych, więc najnowsze dzieło w zupełnie innej kategorii nieco mnie zdziwiło. Ale, będąc zagorzałą fanką jej twórczości, bez wahania sięgnęłam również po tę świeżutką powieść. I oczywiście się nie zawiodłam. Książka jest przede wszystkim pełna poczucia humoru i absurdu, które po prostu uwielbiam. Wielokrotnie podczas czytania chrumkałam pod nosem niekontrolowanym śmiechem.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Rodzina Trawnych bardzo szybko zyskuje sympatię, gdyż łatwo się z nimi utożsamiać. Ja osobiście w Teresce znalazłam bratnią duszę, z jej uzależnieniem od kasztanków i kawy (któż może ją winić?), awersji do wysiłku...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/dywan/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/dywan/</guid>
        
        <category>Dywan z wkladką</category>
        
        <category>Marta Kisiel</category>
        
        <category>W.A.B.</category>
        
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Inscape</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Inscape” is a solo debut cyberpunk thriller by Louise Carey. Tanta is a promising agent of the InTech corporation, and she’s beyond excited when she is dispatched on her first critical mission. But what was supposed to be a simple task of retrieving a stolen hard drive turns out to be a disaster. As one of two survivors, Tanta is thrown deep into the intrigue that is far beyond what she was expecting.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The author takes us to the future, where after the catastrophic Meltdown, the world was changed forever. Corporations took over the reins and ruled their designated areas...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/inscape/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/inscape/</guid>
        
        <category>Inscape</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Louise Carey</category>
        
        <category>cyberpunk</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
