<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kamila reads</title>
    <description>I'm Kamila and I love books! If you looking for book recommendations you can check out my blog and see what I'm reading!</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 13:19:53 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 13:19:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Poison River Legend of the Five Rings A Daidoji Shin Mystery</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Poison River: Legend of the Five Rings: A Daidoji Shin Mystery” by Joshua Reynolds is a novel from a fictional world created for a card game “Legend of the Five Rings” (L5R). It was the second novel from this universe that I’ve read, and although it had a different vibe than “Curse of Honor”, I enjoyed it as well.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This time we the author takes us to a very peculiar location – the City of the Rich Frog. It is unique because it doesn’t belong to any of the great clans exclusively. Three of them – Lion, Unicorn and Dragon...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/poisonriver/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/poisonriver/</guid>
        
        <category>Poison River</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Legend of the Five Ring</category>
        
        <category>A Daidoji Shin Mystery</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Płacz</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Płacz” Marty Kisiel to trzeci tom “Cyklu Wrocławskiego”. Ponownie spotykamy tu grono naszych ulubionych bohaterów, wszystkie trzy panny, Stern oraz siostry Bolesne. Powieść zaczyna się dość niewinnie. Po wydarzeniach z “Toń” drogi przyjaciół się rozeszły i wszyscy zgodnie udają, że to normalne. Dopiero wołanie z zaświatów mobilizuje postaci to ponownego połączenia sił.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Cała akcja rozgrywa się w Górach Sowich, miejscu pełnym legend, tajemnic i niewyjaśnionych zagadek. Autorka bardzo umiejętnie kreowała mistyczną atmosferę przeplatając wątki fantastyczne, jak przeskoki w czasie, z faktycznymi historiami, które miały miejsce w tym regionie. Po przeczytaniu tej książki aż się chce samemu odwiedzić te miejsca i...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/placz/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/placz/</guid>
        
        <category>Płacz</category>
        
        <category>Marta Kisiel</category>
        
        <category>Cykl Wrocławski</category>
        
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rhythm of War</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Rhythm of War” is the fourth book in the most epic fantasy saga “The Stormlight Archive” by Brandon Sanderson. Thanks to Gollancz I’m the part of the UK Blog Tour, celebrating the release of this long-awaited book. I will share my impressions with you after reading the first part of the novel (there are five parts in total, around 1200 pages, so brace yourselves!).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I was waiting for “Rhythm of War” since I finished reading “Oathbringer” back in 2017, so I was beyond excited when the book finally landed in my hands! Like all the other books in the series,...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/rhythmofwar/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/rhythmofwar/</guid>
        
        <category>Rhythm of War</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>The Stormlight Archive</category>
        
        <category>Gollancz</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gdziekolwiek Spojrzysz</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;„Gdziekolwiek Spojrzysz” autorstwa Jakuba Szamałka to ostatni już tom serii „Ukryta Sieć”.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Tym razem akcja powieści zawiązuje się w Żelaznej Górze, gdzie dochodzi do katastrofalnego w skutkach wycieku na terenie kopalni miedzi. Cóż mogło być przyczyną tego wypadku, skoro żadne przeglądy techniczne nie wykazały najmniejszych usterek? I jaki interes ma Amerykańska firma oferując sprzątanie po całym zdarzeniu za przysłowiowy bezcen?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Tymczasem Julita również nie spoczywa na laurach. Wciąż śledząc złoczyńców, na których trop trafiła w pierwszej powieści, odkrywa ich podejrzane zainteresowanie zbiorami bibliotecznymi i inwestycje w generatory tekstu. Jaki związek może to mieć z ich poprzednimi zbrodniami i co takiego...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/gdziekolwiekspojrzysz/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/gdziekolwiekspojrzysz/</guid>
        
        <category>Gdziekolwiek Spojrzysz</category>
        
        <category>Jakub Szamałek</category>
        
        <category>Ukryta Sieć</category>
        
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Left-Handed Booksellers of London</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Left-Handed Booksellers of London” by Garth Nix is a surprising adventure in a slightly alternative London in 1983. The Protagonist, Susan Arkshaw, is searching for her father, and following the small trail leading to one of London’s crime lords. Unfortunately, before she manages to ask him any question, he is turned to a pile of dust by a handsome young man named Merlin. From that moment, Susan discovers a whole new world that has always existed just under the nose of regular people.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;From the very first chapters, the weird things keep popping up at you. I love how...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/booksellers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/booksellers/</guid>
        
        <category>The Left-Handed Booksellers of London</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Garth Nix</category>
        
        <category>Gollancz</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The City of Runes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The City of Runes”, debiutancka powieść Dagmary Drozdowskiej, to pełna przygód opowieść o poszukiwaniach zaginionego skarbu wikingów. Jako ciekawostkę dodam, że autorka została laureatką konkursu Pen to Print Book Challenge Competition. Opowieść przypadła do gustu jurorom na tyle, że nagrodzili Dagmarę wydaniem pełnej wersji powieści. Jest ot bardzo inspirująca historia sukcesu i jeśli jesteście ciekawi szczegółów, możecie bez wahania zagadać autorkę na jej mediach społecznościowych.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Dr Erika Skyberg jest zadowolona ze swojego dotychczasowego życia. Jest kuratorem w Muzeum Wikingów w Oslo i w środowisku zawodowym jest znana jako ekspert w swojej dziedzinie. Jedynym mankamentem jest jej absolutny brak szczęścia w...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/thecityofbones/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thecityofbones/</guid>
        
        <category>The City of Runes</category>
        
        <category>Dagmara Drozdowska</category>
        
        <category>mitologia nordycka</category>
        
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The City of Runes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The City of Runes” by Dragmara Drozdowska is a fast-paced adventure through myths and legends. The book is a debut novel; the author was shortlisted in the Pen to Print Book Challenge Competition. The story captivated the jury, and as an award, the novel was published. This is a truly inspiring success story and if you wish to know more, don’t hesitate to reach to Dagmara on social media.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Dr Erika Skyberg is living her dream life. She is a curator in a Viking museum in Oslo and is well known as an expert in her field. The only downside...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/thecityofrunes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thecityofrunes/</guid>
        
        <category>The City of Runes</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Dagmara Drozdowska</category>
        
        <category>norse mythology</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Paris Library</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Paris Library” by Janet Skeslien Charles is a novel based on the true stories of Parisian librarians during WWII. The most important place here belongs to the books themselves, of course. You’ll find here lots of beautiful quotes for different authors and suitable for every mood.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The author research the history of the American Library in Paris thoroughly, working on old letters memoirs and also talking to the family of those who worked there during WWII. All this effort shows in the book, as we are aware that the characters were real people living their lives in those difficult...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/theparislibrary/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/theparislibrary/</guid>
        
        <category>The Paris Library</category>
        
        <category>Janet Skeslien Charles</category>
        
        <category>historical fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Heart so Fierce and Broken</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“A Heart so Fierce and Broken” written by Brigid Kemmerer is the second book in “Cursebreakers” series. Please be aware that this review will include spoilers to the first book, so if you haven’t read it yet, I suggest leaving this review for later.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Harper succeeded in her impossible task – she has broken the vicious curse that tormented Prince Rhen for as long as he could remember. But unfortunately, there is no happily ever after for them. The kingdom is in extremely poor condition after years of neglect and continuous advances from their ferocious neighbour Syhl Shallow. Even though...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/aheartsofierceandbroken/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/aheartsofierceandbroken/</guid>
        
        <category>A Heart so Fierce and Broken</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Brigid Kemmerer</category>
        
        <category>Cursebreakers</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Curse of Honor - A Legend of the Five Rings Novel</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Curse of Honor - A Legend of the Five Rings Novel” by David Annandale is the first full-size novel placed in the fantastic world of Rokugan, created by Fantasy Flight Games. I wanted to read this book because I’m familiar with the card game (which I play quite often with my husband) and I love this world and its elaborate lore. I have to note I am not a hardcore fan – I haven’t read all released novellas and don’t follow on significant world events that are happening in Rokugan. But even if you don’t know this fandom rest assured...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/curseofhonor/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/curseofhonor/</guid>
        
        <category>Curse of Honor</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>David Annandale</category>
        
        <category>Legend of the Five Rings</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>House of Earth and Blood</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;„House of Earth and Blood” was a long-awaited new novel by Sarah J Maas. This time the author gives us not a young adult, but an urban fantasy for adults. The main difference between this book and popular ACOTAR series is putting action in the modern world. Although we still have Maas’s trademarked Fae race, we also have here loads of other magical and non-magical creatures – angels, demons, shapeshifters, vampires and so on. Alongside magic and special abilities, we also have guns, mobile phones, cars and all other technological gadgets that make life easier. Maas fused best elements of...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/houseofearthandblood/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/houseofearthandblood/</guid>
        
        <category>House of Earth and Blood</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Sarah J. Maas</category>
        
        <category>Crescent City</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Seven Devils</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Seven Devils” is a feminist space opera written by Laura Lam and Elizabeth May. It’s a story about seven outstanding characters that are going against overwhelming odds and trying to stand against tyranny of Tholosian Empire.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Firstly, the world created by the authors is ruthless and unjust. In the present, most of the humans are genetically designed for specific roles. The ruling Tholosian Empire creates the perfect workforce, soldiers, engineers and so on, providing them with genes enhancing brain or physical power, depending on current needs. But creating an ideal human being needs a lot of work and experiments, so...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/sevendevils/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sevendevils/</guid>
        
        <category>Seven Devils</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Laura Lam</category>
        
        <category>Elizabeth May</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Caliban's War</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Caliban’s War “is the second book in “The Expanse” series by James S. A. Corey. The story continues with well known high pace and high stakes action. We start at Ganymede, were a Martian soldier is faced with a monstrous creature, who slaughter the whole platoon of soldiers in seconds. The even triggers long-held hostilities between Mars and Earth, and as a result, the neutral Ganymede suffers from disastrous collateral damage. And amid chaos and panic, a child is taken away from a loving parent.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Holden and the crew of Rocinante are obviously in the middle of everything. While working...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/calibanswar/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/calibanswar/</guid>
        
        <category>Caliban's War</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>James S.A. Corey</category>
        
        <category>The Expanse</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Aurora Burning</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Aurora Burning” by amazing authors duo Jay Kristoff and Amy Kaufman was a book I was waiting for since I finished “Aurora Rising”. I preordered it as soon as it was available and couldn’t wait to have it in my hands finally. Nothing would make me happier than meeting sassy squad 312 and join their adventures once again.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;From the very beginning, the action does not slow down. Facing the looming threat of ancient evil alien race that infiltrated human’s intelligence agency already and are going to devour the whole galaxy is not an easy task. We should also add...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/auroraburning/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/auroraburning/</guid>
        
        <category>Aurora Burning</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Jay Kristoff</category>
        
        <category>Amie Kaufman</category>
        
        <category>The Aurora Cycle</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Loneliest Girl in the Universe</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Loneliest Girl in the Universe” by Lauren James is a story about a girl who is the only surviving crew member on a spaceship, heading to another planet to establish a new colony for humans. Can you even imagine how lonely it must be? And besides, she is only a teenager with not only a spaceship to maintain, but also tasked with raising new civilisation among the stars. But no pressure.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In the beginning, we learn about Romy daily routines. She was born abroad her spaceship, so she doesn’t know anything about regular life on Earth and can only...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/theloneliestgirlintheuniverse/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/theloneliestgirlintheuniverse/</guid>
        
        <category>The Loneliest Girl in the Universe</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Lauren James</category>
        
        <category>YA sci-fi</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Queen of Nothing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Queen of Nothing” is the last novel in “The Folk of the Air” series by Holly Black. If you haven’t read previous books, please do not proceed with this review as it contains spoilers to first two tomes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;After a surprising turn of event in “The Wicked King” Jude Durate finds herself exiled in the mortal world. She is furious, full of hate and self-loathing because she let herself be tricked like that. She doesn’t sit around, though. She quickly made a connection with Folk residing in the human realm and got herself stable income by picking up jobs,...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/thequeenofnothing/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thequeenofnothing/</guid>
        
        <category>The Queen of Nothing</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Holly Black</category>
        
        <category>The Folk of the Air</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Warbreaker</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;‘Warbreaker’ was the first Sanderson’s book I’ve ever read. It would never pick it up myself, the old polish edition was so ugly, I would never look twice at it in a bookstore. But I got it as a gift, so I gave it a shot. And I was mesmerised and promised myself to read more of his book. Now I’ve read almost all of them, and I’m waiting impatiently for new releases. After all these years, I decided to reread ‘Warbreaker’ to see how my perception of the book changed after all this time. And yes, I did buy...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/warbreaker/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/warbreaker/</guid>
        
        <category>Warbreaker</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Brandon Sanderson</category>
        
        <category>Cosmere</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Howling Dark</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Howling Dark” is a second book in “Sun Eater” series by Christopher Ruocchio. Hadrian’s epic adventures continue, and this time he is taking us to the very borders of the known universe, to the dark space inhabited by creatures feared by all Sollan Empire.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Hadrian is doing everything to fulfil his mission and dream of finding a mysterious planet Vorgossos and contact the elusive race of Cielcin. But even if he finds it, will he be able to stop the war that was menacing the human for hundreds of years now? Can the aliens be reason with, or they are...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/howlingdark/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/howlingdark/</guid>
        
        <category>Howling Dark</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Christopher Ruocchio</category>
        
        <category>Sun Eater</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Last Stand</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Last Stand” is the last book in “The Black Mage” series by Rachel E. Carter. The review contains spoilers to first three tomes of the series so please do not read unless you read them.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;After dramatic events in “Candidate”, Ryiah found herself in a perilous situation. She discovered the truth about nefarious plans of new king Blane, but she doesn’t have any proof to back up her accusations. But she can’t turn a blind eye to Jerar’s people suffering. The young mage decides to support the rebels and use her power as Prince’s wife to sway the ruler of...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/laststand/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/laststand/</guid>
        
        <category>Last Stand</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Rachel E. Carter</category>
        
        <category>The Black Mage</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Swords of Silence</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;„The Swords of Silence” is a historical novel written by Shaun Curry. I was really intrigued when I found this book on NetGalley. Even though it’s not fantasy (that’s how it was categorised there), Japanese culture always seems interesting for me, so I requested this book right away.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The book is starting with a scene in the prologue where Japanese magister is crucifying and burning Christian prisoners. That gives us the feeling of the times where the action is set for the novel. Other religions are no longer accepted in Japan, as Shogun sees them, especially Christianity, as a threat...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/theswordsofsilence/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/theswordsofsilence/</guid>
        
        <category>The Swords of Silence</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Shaun Curry</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Chestnut Man</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Chestnut Man’ is a dark thriller by Søren Sveistrup placed in Denmark. Copenhagen is terrorised by a psychopath brutally murdering woman. On the crime scene, police find a little chestnut man with fingerprints of a girl long thought dead. Is it possible that the old mystery was not fully resolved? Who is brilliant chestnut men creator who keeps eluding the police? The case is given to bright Naia Thulin and Mark Hess, who was temporarily sent back to Denmark from Europol. Will they be able to solve the case before the serial killer fulfil his dark plan and kill...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/kasztanowyludzik/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/kasztanowyludzik/</guid>
        
        <category>The Chestnut Man</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Søren Sveistrup</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kimkolwiek Jesteś</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Kimkolwiek jesteś” Jakuba Szamałka jest kontynuacją thrillera „Cokolwiek wybierzesz”. Julita Wójcicka, obecnie poważana dziennikarka śledcza, podąża za tropem nieuchwytnego administratora forum pornograficznego uwikłanego w wiele brudnych spraw. Niestety jej śledztwo stoi w miejscu i nie zapowiada się, by nagle odkryła jakieś nowe wskazówki. W międzyczasie kobieta postanawia zbadać sprawę morderstwa camgirl, która być może jest jakoś powiązana z tajemniczym złoczyńcą. Szybko okazuje się, że nowe śledztwo będzie równie niebezpieczne, jak sprawa Buczka.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;W kolejnej części serii „Ukryta Sieć” ponownie spotykamy się z dobrze znanymi nam bohaterami: Julitą, Jankiem oraz Leonem, mamy tu również kilka nowych postaci, które grają znaczące role....</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/kimkolwiekjestes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/kimkolwiekjestes/</guid>
        
        <category>Kimkolwiek Jesteś</category>
        
        <category>Jakub Szamałek</category>
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
        <category>Ukryta Sieć</category>
        
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fałszywy Pieśniarz</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Fałszywy Pieśniarz” to ostatni tom trylogii „Szamanka od Umarlaków” Martyny Raduchowskiej. Akcja rozpoczyna się wkrótce po zakończeniu poprzedniego tomu. Ida, która zdecydowała się kontynuować współpracę z WONem, próbuje rozwikłać wszystkie tajemnice Demona Luster, co nie jest jednak proste. Śledztwo utknęło w martwym punkcie, a sama Ida czuje się w nowej pracy jak dziwadło, którego nikt nie rozumie. Kiedy jednak następuje przełom, sprawy przybierają bardzo niefortunny obrót.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ostatnia odsłona cyklu jest zdecydowanie najmroczniejszą i najbardziej depresyjną ze wszystkich książek. Od początku do końca wszystko idzie źle i jeszcze gorzej. Kolejne przeszkody nie do przejścia piętrzą się bez końca a perspektywy na...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/falszywypiesniarz/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/falszywypiesniarz/</guid>
        
        <category>Fałszywy Pieśniarz</category>
        
        <category>Martyna Raduchowska</category>
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
        <category>Szamanka od Umarlaków</category>
        
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Witchwood Crown</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;„The Witchwood Crown” is the newest novel from Tad Williams starting new series “The Last King of Osten Ard” and is a sequel to well known “Memory, Sorrow, and Thorn”. After many years of events in the original trilogy and defeating the great evil, everyone should live peacefully and have their happily ever after, right? Unfortunately, our characters won’t be that lucky.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The book is a classical fantasy tale. Unlike popular YA which are strongly action-driven, “The Witchwood Crown” is mesmerising with its world complexity and compelling characters. We have loads of different nations, and each one of them has...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/koronazczarodrzewu/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/koronazczarodrzewu/</guid>
        
        <category>The Witchwood Crown</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Tad Williams</category>
        
        <category>The Last King of Osten Ard</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Demon Luster</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;„Demon Luster” to druga część serii o Idzie Brzezińskiej autorstwa Martyny Raduchowskiej. Jeśli nie czytaliście pierwszego tomu, to proszę, podarujcie sobie tę recenzję, bo będzie pełna spojlerów z wydarzeń z „Szamanki od Umarlaków”.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ida znalazła się w bardzo nieciekawej sytuacji. Związana nieśmiertelną przysięgą musi odnaleźć zagubioną w lustrzanym piekle duszę Mikołaja i przeprowadzić ją w zaświaty, bo jeśli zawiedzie, jej dusza obróci się w nicość. Łatwiej powiedzieć niż zrobić, gdyż wedle wszelkich znaków na niebie i ziemi, zagubiony duch znajduje się w szponach seryjnego mordercy, który zaszył się w pełnym czarnej magii lustrzanym świecie i aktualnie wysyła hordy demonów, by...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/demonluster/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/demonluster/</guid>
        
        <category>Demon Luster</category>
        
        <category>Martyna Raduchowska</category>
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
        <category>Szamanka od Umarlaków</category>
        
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Shadow Saint</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Shadow Saint” is the continuation of “The Black Gods Legacy” series. I really enjoyed the first book, so I was very excited to dig into the sequel. Thank you NetGalley and Orbit for the review copy!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The action is picking up a few months after perilous events of “the Gutter Prayer”, called now the Crisis. There is a new city that grows out of nowhere, and no one seems to know what to do with it or how to treat it. Eladora Duttin is working as an aide to Efro Kelkin, and her main task is surveying this unexpected...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/theshadowsaint/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/theshadowsaint/</guid>
        
        <category>The Shadow Saint</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Gareth Ryder-Hanrahan</category>
        
        <category>The Black Iron Legacy</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The God Game</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The God Game” is a novel written by American author Danny Tobey. It has a similar vibe as “Ready Player One”, it’s based in our modern world with advanced AI using it as its playground. It’s an action-packed thriller that will often take you by surprise.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Charlie has been going through a rough time. His mother died, and his father was too weak to deal with the outcome, leaving his son in charge of things no teenager should be facing alone. He is miserable and pretty much gave up on all his plans and ambitions for the future. So, when...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/thegodgame/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thegodgame/</guid>
        
        <category>The God Game</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Danny Tobey</category>
        
        <category>Gollancz</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Phasma</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I read “Phasma” by Delilah S. Dawson because with all the hype for the new Star Wars movie I felt a great longing to get back to the universe before going to the cinema. So, as I had this book in my collection for a while now, I decided it is high time to read it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Phasma is one of the officers in the First Order. She’s not playing a significant role in the movies, but she’s there, and with her imposing posture and chrome armour she’s quite an intriguing character. So, when I saw the book about her, I...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/phasma/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/phasma/</guid>
        
        <category>Phasma</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Delilah S. Dawson</category>
        
        <category>Star Wars</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Starsight</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Starsight” is a brand-new sequel of Brandon Sanderson’s “Skyward”. A word of advice, if you haven’t read the first book, please don’t look at this review, because it will probably contain loads of spoilers to it. Writing a review of the sequel I would expect the readers know the ending of the previous book. So yeah, you’ve been warned.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;From the very start, “Starsight” is action-filled. We find Spensa in the middle of a space battle, fighting with merciless Krells. But the story takes a very different turn. I was expecting another book filled with DDF’s desperate attempts to survive,...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/starsight/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/starsight/</guid>
        
        <category>Starsight</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Brandon Sanderson</category>
        
        <category>Skyward</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Imaginary Friend</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Imaginary Friend” is a new novel by Stephen Chbosky. It was written twenty years after the release of his famous work “The Perks of Being the Wallflower”. In the meantime, he was working mostly as a film director and screenwriter. He admitted he missed his writing and that how “Imaginary Friend” was born.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The book itself is huge. I was reading through it slowly, I have an eBook and physical copy, so I could get back to it wherever I was. There are opinions that it is far too long, but I think it’s just the writing style. The author...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/imaginaryfriend/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/imaginaryfriend/</guid>
        
        <category>Imaginary Friend</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Stephen Chbosky</category>
        
        <category>Follow the cloud</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
