<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kamila reads</title>
    <description>I'm Kamila and I love books! If you looking for book recommendations you can check out my blog and see what I'm reading!</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 13:06:51 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 13:06:51 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Howling Dark</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Howling Dark” is a second book in “Sun Eater” series by Christopher Ruocchio. Hadrian’s epic adventures continue, and this time he is taking us to the very borders of the known universe, to the dark space inhabited by creatures feared by all Sollan Empire.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Hadrian is doing everything to fulfil his mission and dream of finding a mysterious planet Vorgossos and contact the elusive race of Cielcin. But even if he finds it, will he be able to stop the war that was menacing the human for hundreds of years now? Can the aliens be reason with, or they are...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/howlingdark/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/howlingdark/</guid>
        
        <category>Howling Dark</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Christopher Ruocchio</category>
        
        <category>Sun Eater</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Last Stand</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Last Stand” is the last book in “The Black Mage” series by Rachel E. Carter. The review contains spoilers to first three tomes of the series so please do not read unless you read them.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;After dramatic events in “Candidate”, Ryiah found herself in a perilous situation. She discovered the truth about nefarious plans of new king Blane, but she doesn’t have any proof to back up her accusations. But she can’t turn a blind eye to Jerar’s people suffering. The young mage decides to support the rebels and use her power as Prince’s wife to sway the ruler of...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/laststand/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/laststand/</guid>
        
        <category>Last Stand</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Rachel E. Carter</category>
        
        <category>The Black Mage</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Swords of Silence</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;„The Swords of Silence” is a historical novel written by Shaun Curry. I was really intrigued when I found this book on NetGalley. Even though it’s not fantasy (that’s how it was categorised there), Japanese culture always seems interesting for me, so I requested this book right away.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The book is starting with a scene in the prologue where Japanese magister is crucifying and burning Christian prisoners. That gives us the feeling of the times where the action is set for the novel. Other religions are no longer accepted in Japan, as Shogun sees them, especially Christianity, as a threat...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/theswordsofsilence/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/theswordsofsilence/</guid>
        
        <category>The Swords of Silence</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Shaun Curry</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Chestnut Man</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Chestnut Man’ is a dark thriller by Søren Sveistrup placed in Denmark. Copenhagen is terrorised by a psychopath brutally murdering woman. On the crime scene, police find a little chestnut man with fingerprints of a girl long thought dead. Is it possible that the old mystery was not fully resolved? Who is brilliant chestnut men creator who keeps eluding the police? The case is given to bright Naia Thulin and Mark Hess, who was temporarily sent back to Denmark from Europol. Will they be able to solve the case before the serial killer fulfil his dark plan and kill...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/kasztanowyludzik/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/kasztanowyludzik/</guid>
        
        <category>The Chestnut Man</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Søren Sveistrup</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kimkolwiek Jesteś</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Kimkolwiek jesteś” Jakuba Szamałka jest kontynuacją thrillera „Cokolwiek wybierzesz”. Julita Wójcicka, obecnie poważana dziennikarka śledcza, podąża za tropem nieuchwytnego administratora forum pornograficznego uwikłanego w wiele brudnych spraw. Niestety jej śledztwo stoi w miejscu i nie zapowiada się, by nagle odkryła jakieś nowe wskazówki. W międzyczasie kobieta postanawia zbadać sprawę morderstwa camgirl, która być może jest jakoś powiązana z tajemniczym złoczyńcą. Szybko okazuje się, że nowe śledztwo będzie równie niebezpieczne, jak sprawa Buczka.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;W kolejnej części serii „Ukryta Sieć” ponownie spotykamy się z dobrze znanymi nam bohaterami: Julitą, Jankiem oraz Leonem, mamy tu również kilka nowych postaci, które grają znaczące role....</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/kimkolwiekjestes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/kimkolwiekjestes/</guid>
        
        <category>Kimkolwiek Jesteś</category>
        
        <category>Jakub Szamałek</category>
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
        <category>Ukryta Sieć</category>
        
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fałszywy Pieśniarz</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Fałszywy Pieśniarz” to ostatni tom trylogii „Szamanka od Umarlaków” Martyny Raduchowskiej. Akcja rozpoczyna się wkrótce po zakończeniu poprzedniego tomu. Ida, która zdecydowała się kontynuować współpracę z WONem, próbuje rozwikłać wszystkie tajemnice Demona Luster, co nie jest jednak proste. Śledztwo utknęło w martwym punkcie, a sama Ida czuje się w nowej pracy jak dziwadło, którego nikt nie rozumie. Kiedy jednak następuje przełom, sprawy przybierają bardzo niefortunny obrót.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ostatnia odsłona cyklu jest zdecydowanie najmroczniejszą i najbardziej depresyjną ze wszystkich książek. Od początku do końca wszystko idzie źle i jeszcze gorzej. Kolejne przeszkody nie do przejścia piętrzą się bez końca a perspektywy na...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/falszywypiesniarz/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/falszywypiesniarz/</guid>
        
        <category>Fałszywy Pieśniarz</category>
        
        <category>Martyna Raduchowska</category>
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
        <category>Szamanka od Umarlaków</category>
        
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Witchwood Crown</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;„The Witchwood Crown” is the newest novel from Tad Williams starting new series “The Last King of Osten Ard” and is a sequel to well known “Memory, Sorrow, and Thorn”. After many years of events in the original trilogy and defeating the great evil, everyone should live peacefully and have their happily ever after, right? Unfortunately, our characters won’t be that lucky.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The book is a classical fantasy tale. Unlike popular YA which are strongly action-driven, “The Witchwood Crown” is mesmerising with its world complexity and compelling characters. We have loads of different nations, and each one of them has...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/koronazczarodrzewu/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/koronazczarodrzewu/</guid>
        
        <category>The Witchwood Crown</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Tad Williams</category>
        
        <category>The Last King of Osten Ard</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Demon Luster</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;„Demon Luster” to druga część serii o Idzie Brzezińskiej autorstwa Martyny Raduchowskiej. Jeśli nie czytaliście pierwszego tomu, to proszę, podarujcie sobie tę recenzję, bo będzie pełna spojlerów z wydarzeń z „Szamanki od Umarlaków”.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ida znalazła się w bardzo nieciekawej sytuacji. Związana nieśmiertelną przysięgą musi odnaleźć zagubioną w lustrzanym piekle duszę Mikołaja i przeprowadzić ją w zaświaty, bo jeśli zawiedzie, jej dusza obróci się w nicość. Łatwiej powiedzieć niż zrobić, gdyż wedle wszelkich znaków na niebie i ziemi, zagubiony duch znajduje się w szponach seryjnego mordercy, który zaszył się w pełnym czarnej magii lustrzanym świecie i aktualnie wysyła hordy demonów, by...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/demonluster/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/demonluster/</guid>
        
        <category>Demon Luster</category>
        
        <category>Martyna Raduchowska</category>
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
        <category>Szamanka od Umarlaków</category>
        
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Shadow Saint</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Shadow Saint” is the continuation of “The Black Gods Legacy” series. I really enjoyed the first book, so I was very excited to dig into the sequel. Thank you NetGalley and Orbit for the review copy!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The action is picking up a few months after perilous events of “the Gutter Prayer”, called now the Crisis. There is a new city that grows out of nowhere, and no one seems to know what to do with it or how to treat it. Eladora Duttin is working as an aide to Efro Kelkin, and her main task is surveying this unexpected...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/theshadowsaint/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/theshadowsaint/</guid>
        
        <category>The Shadow Saint</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Gareth Ryder-Hanrahan</category>
        
        <category>The Black Iron Legacy</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The God Game</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The God Game” is a novel written by American author Danny Tobey. It has a similar vibe as “Ready Player One”, it’s based in our modern world with advanced AI using it as its playground. It’s an action-packed thriller that will often take you by surprise.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Charlie has been going through a rough time. His mother died, and his father was too weak to deal with the outcome, leaving his son in charge of things no teenager should be facing alone. He is miserable and pretty much gave up on all his plans and ambitions for the future. So, when...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/thegodgame/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thegodgame/</guid>
        
        <category>The God Game</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Danny Tobey</category>
        
        <category>Gollancz</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Phasma</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I read “Phasma” by Delilah S. Dawson because with all the hype for the new Star Wars movie I felt a great longing to get back to the universe before going to the cinema. So, as I had this book in my collection for a while now, I decided it is high time to read it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Phasma is one of the officers in the First Order. She’s not playing a significant role in the movies, but she’s there, and with her imposing posture and chrome armour she’s quite an intriguing character. So, when I saw the book about her, I...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/phasma/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/phasma/</guid>
        
        <category>Phasma</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Delilah S. Dawson</category>
        
        <category>Star Wars</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Starsight</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Starsight” is a brand-new sequel of Brandon Sanderson’s “Skyward”. A word of advice, if you haven’t read the first book, please don’t look at this review, because it will probably contain loads of spoilers to it. Writing a review of the sequel I would expect the readers know the ending of the previous book. So yeah, you’ve been warned.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;From the very start, “Starsight” is action-filled. We find Spensa in the middle of a space battle, fighting with merciless Krells. But the story takes a very different turn. I was expecting another book filled with DDF’s desperate attempts to survive,...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/starsight/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/starsight/</guid>
        
        <category>Starsight</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Brandon Sanderson</category>
        
        <category>Skyward</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Imaginary Friend</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Imaginary Friend” is a new novel by Stephen Chbosky. It was written twenty years after the release of his famous work “The Perks of Being the Wallflower”. In the meantime, he was working mostly as a film director and screenwriter. He admitted he missed his writing and that how “Imaginary Friend” was born.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The book itself is huge. I was reading through it slowly, I have an eBook and physical copy, so I could get back to it wherever I was. There are opinions that it is far too long, but I think it’s just the writing style. The author...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/imaginaryfriend/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/imaginaryfriend/</guid>
        
        <category>Imaginary Friend</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Stephen Chbosky</category>
        
        <category>Follow the cloud</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cokolwiek wybierzesz</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;„My już żyjemy w dystopijnej cyberprzyszłości. Tylko interfejs jest przyjazny dla użytkownika, więc nikt się nie zorientował.”&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;„Cokolwiek wybierzesz” to pierwszy tom cyklu „Ukryta sieć” autorstwa Jakuba Szamałka. Jest to trzymający w napięciu thriller, który przedstawia nam nowy, bardzo aktualny, rodzaj przestępczości, opierającej się na wykorzystaniu nowoczesnych technologii.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Julita jest dziennikarką z wielkimi ambicjami, pracującą dla plotkarskiego portalu Meganewsy, który żyje głównie skandalami celebrytów. Pewnego dnia dostaje jednak zlecenie napisania „prawdziwego” newsa o śmiertelnym wypadku Ryszarda Buczka, słynnego prowadzącego programu dla dzieci. Upojona sukcesem pragnie wykorzystać swoje pięć minut i zaczyna przyglądać się wydarzeiu uważniej. Ku własnemu zaskoczeniu, im dłużej...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/cokolwiekwybierzesz/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/cokolwiekwybierzesz/</guid>
        
        <category>Cokolwiek wybierzesz</category>
        
        <category>Jakub Szamałek</category>
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
        <category>Ukryta Sieć</category>
        
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rithmatist</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In an alternate world, America is divided into small islands. In the middle of them, all is Nebrask – a dangerous place. It was infested by the Wild Chalklings who terrorise local people leaving only ruins and mutilated corpses in their wake. The single line of defence is Rithmatists, people with a rare talent to make their chalk drawings come to life and keep the wild creatures at bay. That’s why there are eight different schools responsible for training them, located on different islands.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Joel is a student in one of them, Armedius Academy. Unfortunately, he wan’s chosen to become...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/rytmatysta/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/rytmatysta/</guid>
        
        <category>Rithmatist</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Brandon Sanderson</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Port of Shadows</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;‘Port of Shadows’ is the newest novel by Glen Cook from the Black Company universe. It is published almost twenty years after the original series. The story is taking place after events of the first anthology ‘The Chronicles of Black Company’. I was excited about this book because I quite enjoyed the original series.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In the beginning, it’s not clear what exactly this book is about. We have here three main plots: current situation, where the Black Company is station in a small town and not doing anything important; a story of a necromancer, whose greatest dream is to fully...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/portofshadows/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/portofshadows/</guid>
        
        <category>Port of Shadows</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Glen Cook</category>
        
        <category>The Black Company</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Na moment przed świtem</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;„Na moment przed świtem” to pierwszy tom nowego cyklu Magdaleny Wali „Za zakrętem”.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Jest to powieść obyczajowa, w której śledzimy losy dwóch kobiet, nieszczęśliwej Adrianny i Agnes, Ślązaczki w bardzo podeszłym wieku. Młodsza z kobiet tkwi w małżeństwie, gdzie traktowana jest jak niewolnica, gotowa na każde skinienie męża. Poznając jednak historię młodości Agnes, która przeżyła drugą wojnę światową, uświadamia sobie, że być może jej życie nie jest jeszcze zaprzepaszczone i podejmuje walkę o własne szczęście. Chociaż w tym celu będzie musiała zmierzyć się z bolesną przeszłością.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Książka jest lekka i czyta się ją bardzo szybko. Szczególnie podobały mi się fragmenty...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/namomentprzedswitem/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/namomentprzedswitem/</guid>
        
        <category>Na moment przed świtem</category>
        
        <category>Magdalena Wala</category>
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
        <category>Za zakrętem</category>
        
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Permanent Record</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Edward “Ed” Snowden is an American computer professional who worked for CIA and leaked classified data about mass surveillance programs to journalists, who then made them public. If you think about it, it sounds like a good story for a spy novel. But what it makes it more interesting, is that it really happened. In 2013 the news broke, and the world was shocked to discover that American government was collecting an enormous amount of data, all the emails, phone calls and text from a regular people all over the world. After six years of Snowden in ‘Permanent record’ shares...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/permanentrecord/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/permanentrecord/</guid>
        
        <category>Permanent Record</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Edward Snowden</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Szamanka od umarlaków</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;„Szamanka od Umarlaków” Martyny Raduchowskiej to pełna humoru opowieść o mrocznej tematyce. Ida Brzezińska pochodzi z wielkiego rodu czarodziejów, ale sama nie wykazuje za grosz zdolności magicznych. W ramach buntu postanawia uciec do Wrocławia na studia psychologiczne i rozpocząć wymarzone, samodzielne życie, wolne od zabobonów i przesądów. Okazuje się jednak, że nie będzie to takie proste, gdyż Ida zaczyna dostrzegać martwych ludzi wszędzie wokół siebie. A na domiar złego, oni wcale nie chcą zrozumieć, że ona może nie mieć ochoty z nimi rozmawiać. Na szczęście z pomocą przychodzi jej ekscentryczna ciotka Tekla, która przyjmuje ją pod swoje skrzydła.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ida, oprócz...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/szamanka/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/szamanka/</guid>
        
        <category>Szamanka od umarlaków</category>
        
        <category>Martyna Raduchowska</category>
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Angel Mage</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;‘Angel Mage’ is the newest fantasy novel by Garth Nix. It’s a stand-alone with a very original magic system based on summoning angels and using their powers. I was hooked from the very first pages.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Liliath was a very talented icon maker with extraordinary powers, but with a fall of her state and its archangel disappearance, she was forced to flee and run for her life. She goes into a magically induced sleep to wait for a convenient time to get back and restore the fallen angel to its glorious power. And make their enemies pay.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Four young people who...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/angelmage/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/angelmage/</guid>
        
        <category>Angel Mage</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Garth Nix</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lost and Found</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;‘Lost and Found’ is a new novel written by Orson Scott Card. Contrary to most of his book, this is not a sci-fi or fantasy story, but Young Adult contemporary with a little bit sparkle of everyday magic. I didn’t know what to expect of this book, but as I’m a big fan of the author himself, I had to check it out.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It’s a story about fourteen-year-old boy Ezekiel. He has an exceptional talent of finding lost things and instantly knowing where the owner is. It sounds good in theory, but it quickly turns up to get the boy...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/lostandfound/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/lostandfound/</guid>
        
        <category>Lost and Found</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Orson Scott Card</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Candidate</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;‘Candidate’ by Rachel E. Carter is the third book in ‘The Black Mage’ series, telling a story of Ryiah, a girl from a poor family who dreamed about becoming the legendary Black Mage. I was waiting impatiently for this volume because the ending of the previous one provided us for entirely new perspectives for unravelling this tale.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ryiah is twenty now, and she has already achieved so much it’s unbelievable. Thanks to her extremely hard work she became a black mage, she saved the kingdom from Caltoh’s sneaky attack and in the meantime, she managed to win prince’s heart and...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/candidate/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/candidate/</guid>
        
        <category>Candidate</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Rachel E. Carter</category>
        
        <category>The Black Mage</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Last Command</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;‘The Last Command’ is the last book in ‘Star Wars: The Thrawn Trilogy’ series by Timothy Zahn. It’s an explosive conclusion of the conflict between the New Republic and Imperium lead by Thrawn. Who will be the winner? Does Republic stand a chance against the military genius of the last Imperial Grand Admiral?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A lot is happening in the last book. Imperium is using their newly acquired ships populated with clone soldiers to breaking through New Republic’s defence and taking over planets from their jurisdiction. With their main advantage of more significant military resources gone, the former Rebels becomes desperate...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/thelastcommand/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thelastcommand/</guid>
        
        <category>The Last Command</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Timothy Zahn</category>
        
        <category>Star Wars The Thrawn Trilogy</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Empire of Silence</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;‘Empire of Silence’ by Christopher Ruocchio is the first book in new ‘Sun Eater’ sci-fi series. It was advertised as complex as ‘Dune’ and atmospheric as ‘The Shadow of the Wind’. I usually don’t like comparisons to other books on covers, but in this case, it was surprisingly accurate.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In the beginning, we met Hadrian Marlowe, who earned the reputation of a hero and a monster. Currently, he spends his days imprisoned and writing down his memories, since the very start, when he was just a young man, son of influential archon of prosperous planet Delos. Don’t expect any fireworks,...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/empireofsilence/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/empireofsilence/</guid>
        
        <category>Empire of Silence</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Christoper Ruocchio</category>
        
        <category>Sun Eater</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kolory zła. Czerwień</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Kolory zła. Czerwień” to najnowsza powieść kryminalna Małgorzaty Oliwii Sobczak. Akcja dzieje się w Sopocie i historię poznajemy dwutorowo, wydarzenia z lat 90ych przeplatają się z teraźniejszością. Na sopockiej plaży zostaje znalezione ciało młodej kobiety, okaleczone w pewien szczególny sposób. Do złudzenia przypomina to morderstwo sprzed 17 lat, którego sprawca nigdy nie został złapany. Czy to możliwe, że zbrodniarz ponownie ujawnił się po tak długim czasie? Czy może jest to sprawka naśladowcy? Leopold Bilski, młody prokurator wraz ze swymi współpracownikami postanawia za wszelką cenę znaleźć sprawcę wierząc, że jeśli rozwikła zagadkę z przeszłości, pomoże to również w aktualnym śledztwie.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Książkę...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/czerwien/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/czerwien/</guid>
        
        <category>Kolory zła. Czerwień</category>
        
        <category>Małgorzata Oliwia Sobczak</category>
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
        <category>Kryminał</category>
        
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dziecko Odyna</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;„Dziecko Odyna” autorstwa Siri Pettersen to pierwszy tom cyklu „Krucze Pierścienie”. Autorka zabiera nas w niesamowitą podróż do inspirowanego folklorem skandynawskim świata Ym, gdzie istnieje jedenaście krain a jego mieszkańcy, aetlingowie, wyglądają zupełnie jak ludzie, ale mają też ogony, z których są bardzo dumni oraz mogą korzystać z Evny, przepełniającej cały ich świat magii.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Hirka ma piętnaście lat i zawsze była traktowana jak odmieniec, gdyż sama nie posiada ogona. Zawsze wierzyła w historię, którą opowiadał jej ojciec, że odgryzły go wilki, gdy była niemowlęciem. Jednak wraz z nadciągającym Rytuałem, któremu poddają się wszyscy młodzi ludzi dziewczyna staje się coraz bardziej...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/dzieckoodyna/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/dzieckoodyna/</guid>
        
        <category>Dziecko Odyna</category>
        
        <category>Siri Pettersen</category>
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
        <category>Krucze Pierścienie</category>
        
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Crown Tower</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Crown Tower” by Michael J. Sullivan is the first book in “The Riyria Chronicles”. It is a sequel to “The Riyria Revelations” series (which was published first), and it tells the story of Hadrian and Royce from the very beginning. I like reading from the chronological order of the story, so I started with this one.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Hadrian Blackwater has nothing to fight for anymore. He was a soldier in different armies and killed loads of people across half of the world. But he is bone tired and fed up with this existence. When he receives a letter informing about...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/thecrowntower/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thecrowntower/</guid>
        
        <category>The Crown Tower</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Michael J. Sullivan</category>
        
        <category>The Riyria Chronicles</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kingdom of Souls</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;‘Kingdom of Souls’ is the first YA Fantasy novel by Rena Barron. And what a fantastic debut it is! I requested the ARC of this book from NetGalley because I was intrigued by a story about witchdoctor. That’s not a popular theme for fantasy books, it made this one stands out from the very beginning.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Arrah is born to a family of powerful witchdoctors. Her parents and her grandmother are the most magickly gifted people in all tribes. But so far, all she can do is seeing traces of magic in the air, but she can’t command it. And with...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/kingdomofsouls/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/kingdomofsouls/</guid>
        
        <category>Kingdom of Souls</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Rena Barron</category>
        
        <category>The Last Witchdoctor</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Gone World</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;‘The Gone World’ by Tom Sweterlitsch is a fusion of sci-fi and mystery novel. I’m personally a fan of both genres so I couldn’t wait to read it. The story began in 1997. Shannon Moss, who works for Naval Criminal Investigative Service, is given a case of former SEAL marine family murder. On the site, she also discovers that his teenage daughter went missing, and she is determined to find the girl alive. Everything gets more complicated, when it turns out, that missing SEAL was also participating in Deep Travel assignments, meaning he was travelling to the future. Shannon is...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/goneworld/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/goneworld/</guid>
        
        <category>The Gone World</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Tom Sweterlitsch</category>
        
        <category>Time Travel</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Empress Orchid</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Empress Orchid is a history-based novel written by Anchee Min. We learn about the life of Empress Dowager Cixi, her early life and how she came into the power in the Chinese government. It is an exciting story, considering the complicated political situation the country was after the Opium Wars. Young Orchid is desperate to escape an arranged marriage with her opium-addicted cousin volunteer to herself as a candidate for an imperial concubine. What seemed to be a long shot surprisingly pays out. She is not only approved as a worthy contender but also manage to catch the attention of...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/empressorchid/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/empressorchid/</guid>
        
        <category>Empress Orchid</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Anchee Min</category>
        
        <category>Historical Fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
