<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kamila reads</title>
    <description>I'm Kamila and I love books! If you looking for book recommendations you can check out my blog and see what I'm reading!</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 09:22:08 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 09:22:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Snapshot</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Snapshot” by Brandon Sanderson is a short detective/sci-fi story. Anthony Davis is a cop assigned to the Snapshot Duty.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is another fantastic idea of the author. In the near future, people came up with a way to recreate the specific day in time for the whole city. Police use this for their investigations – to track down the criminals, finding additional clues and so on. The protagonist and his partner are tasked with a simple case, one of their regular duties, but Davis is not satisfied. He saw traces of serious investigation he wasn’t told about, and he decided...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/snapshot/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/snapshot/</guid>
        
        <category>Snapshot</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Brandon Sanderson</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hall of Bones</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Hall of Bones” by Tim Hardie is a debut epic fantasy novel and the first book in the series “The Brotherhood of the Eagle”. I received a copy of the text from the author in exchange for an honest review. I have to say I was a bit weary, as, with debut books, it’s often hit-or-miss. But I liked the synopsis and felt like reading some epic fantasy in a Viking setting, so I gave it a shot. And I have to say I was positively surprised. If I didn’t know any better, I would never guess it was the...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/hallofbones/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/hallofbones/</guid>
        
        <category>Hall of Bones</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Tim Hardie</category>
        
        <category>The Brotherhood of the Eagle</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Abaddon's Gate</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Abaddon’s Gate” is the third book in “The Expanse” series. After the alien artefact builds the massive structure near Uranus, all the factions – Earth, Mars and the Asteroid Belt sent their envoys there, though no one is sure what to do with the strange Gate. Of course, Holden and his crew also find themselves on the way there. But the captain on the Rocinante doesn’t know yet, that someone is plotting to destroy him mercilessly.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For me, this book was not as good as the first two volumes. We have all new characters here: Melba, Bull and Anna, and...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/abaddonsgate/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/abaddonsgate/</guid>
        
        <category>Abaddon's Gate</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>James S. A. Corey</category>
        
        <category>The Expanse</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wezwij Sokoła</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Wezwij Sokoła” to pierwszy tom nowego cyklu “Śniący” autorstwa Maggie Stiefvater. Autorka znana jest przede wszystkim z serii o Kruczych Chłopcach i nowa książka jest poniekąd jej kontynuacją. Tym razem będziemy śledzić losy Ronana Lyncha i jego braci. Żeby sięgnąć po cykl “Śniący” nie jest konieczna znajomość poprzednich książek autorki, gdyż przeszłość Ronana jest tu wspomniana mimochodem, jednak dla fanów Kruczych Chłopców kolejne przygody jednego z bohaterów będą na pewno nie lada gratką.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;“Wezwij Sokoła” skupia się głównie na śniących i ich mocach. Sam pomysł bardzo mi się podobał, Ronan jako całkiem nieźle wyszkolony śniący potrafi zmaterializować w rzeczywistym świecie...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/wezwijsokola/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/wezwijsokola/</guid>
        
        <category>Wezwij Sokoła</category>
        
        <category>Maggie Stiefvater</category>
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
        <category>Śniący</category>
        
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Zodiaki. Genokracja</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Zodiaki. Genokracja” autorstwa Magdaleny Kucenty to powieść w klimacie biopunku. Świat został na zawsze odmieniony po wybuchu zarazy zwanej Pandorą, ludzie cierpią na niekontrolowane mutacje, środowisko zostało zanieczyszczone na tyle, że powstały miasta kryjące się pod ochronnymi kopułami. Społeczeństwo, które wyewoluowało z gruzów znanej nam cywilizacji jest zupełnie nowym gatunkiem.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Świat stworzony przez autorkę jest naprawdę bogaty i różnorodny. Czytając książkę od razu można zauważyć, że to, co widzimy śledząc losy bohaterów to tylko wierzchołek góry lodowej, a reszta wciąż czeka na odkrycie. Tytułowe Zodiaki zostały powołane do życia w laboratorium, ku szczytnemu celowi nieustannego udoskonalania rasy ludzkiej. Jednak jak...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/zodiaki/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/zodiaki/</guid>
        
        <category>Zodiaki. Genokracja</category>
        
        <category>Magdalena Kucenty</category>
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Poppy War</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Poppy War” by R. F. Kuang is a fantasy novel based on modern China history. Rin is a war orphan raised by the smugglers in poor Rooster province in the south, rural part of the Empire. To escape the arranged marriage, she put everything in preparing herself for the Keju – the exam that allows all those who pass attend the Academies. Thanks to her dedication and strong will, she is given a life-changing opportunity.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;“The Poppy War” is a long and complex story. It’s starting with a well-known trope. A poor orphan girl is attending an elite school,...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/thepoppywar/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thepoppywar/</guid>
        
        <category>The Poppy War</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>R. F. Kuang</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Siege and Storm</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Siege and Storm” is the second book in the “Shadow and Bone Trilogy” by Leigh Bardugo. I’ve read the first one more than a year ago, and somehow never got time to continue the series. Still, with upcoming TV series, I decided it’s high time to finish it mainly because I’m a devoted fan of “Six of Crows” duology.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I enjoy getting into the Grishaverse – the world that the author created. And I love that she called the genre tsarpunk – a mixture of high fantasy, 19th-century Russian culture and steampunk. I find it entirely accurate. This unique setting...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/siegeandstorm/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/siegeandstorm/</guid>
        
        <category>Siege and Storm</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Leigh Bardugo</category>
        
        <category>Grishaverse</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Night Parade of 100 Demons</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Night Parade of 100 Demons” by Marie Brennan is a fantasy novel based in Rokugan, the world from Legend of the Five Rings universe. It is firmly based on a feudal Japan, but also includes elements of other Asian cultures as well as magic.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Dragon Clan’s samurai, Agasha no Isao Ryotora, travels to help the remote village deep in the mountains. During the full moon, horrifying creatures of all kinds are attacking the settlement wreaking havoc wherever they go. He finds the situation is far worse than he expected and is also surprised to see another samurai already on...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/thenightparade/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thenightparade/</guid>
        
        <category>The Night Parade of 100 Demons</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Marie Brennan</category>
        
        <category>Legend of the Five Rings</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dywan z wkładką</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Dywan z wkładką” to komedia kryminalna autorstwa Marty Kisiel. Ałtorka przyzwyczaiła nas do książek pełnych elementów fantastycznych, więc najnowsze dzieło w zupełnie innej kategorii nieco mnie zdziwiło. Ale, będąc zagorzałą fanką jej twórczości, bez wahania sięgnęłam również po tę świeżutką powieść. I oczywiście się nie zawiodłam. Książka jest przede wszystkim pełna poczucia humoru i absurdu, które po prostu uwielbiam. Wielokrotnie podczas czytania chrumkałam pod nosem niekontrolowanym śmiechem.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Rodzina Trawnych bardzo szybko zyskuje sympatię, gdyż łatwo się z nimi utożsamiać. Ja osobiście w Teresce znalazłam bratnią duszę, z jej uzależnieniem od kasztanków i kawy (któż może ją winić?), awersji do wysiłku...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/dywan/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/dywan/</guid>
        
        <category>Dywan z wkladką</category>
        
        <category>Marta Kisiel</category>
        
        <category>W.A.B.</category>
        
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Inscape</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Inscape” is a solo debut cyberpunk thriller by Louise Carey. Tanta is a promising agent of the InTech corporation, and she’s beyond excited when she is dispatched on her first critical mission. But what was supposed to be a simple task of retrieving a stolen hard drive turns out to be a disaster. As one of two survivors, Tanta is thrown deep into the intrigue that is far beyond what she was expecting.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The author takes us to the future, where after the catastrophic Meltdown, the world was changed forever. Corporations took over the reins and ruled their designated areas...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/inscape/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/inscape/</guid>
        
        <category>Inscape</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Louise Carey</category>
        
        <category>cyberpunk</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reaper of Souls</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Reaper of Souls” is the second book in a “Kingdom of Souls” series by Rena Barron. After the disastrous conflict with her sister Efiya, Arrah is left as the last living witch doctor. Driven by guilt, she returns to her hometown to discover she is treated either as a dangerous freak or the chosen prophet of Orishas (gods). To make things worse, she can’t even touch the boy she loves, as their powers continuously clash with each other, causing them pain. When she discovers that there is a possibility that some of the tribes survived, she embarks on a dangerous...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/reaperofsouls/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/reaperofsouls/</guid>
        
        <category>Reaper of Souls</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Rena Barron</category>
        
        <category>Kingdom of Souls</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Alcatraz vs. the Evil Librarians</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Alcatraz vs. the Evil Librarians” by Brandon Sanderson is a fantasy novel for younger readers. I, as an author’s devoted fan, was hesitating for a long time before reading it, as I didn’t think I would like it much, because it is directed mostly for middle graders. But, unexpectedly, I had loads of fun reading it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Alcatraz Smedry is a rather ordinary boy if you ignore the fact that he can break practically anything he touches. He is also a bit unlucky - because of the strange clumsiness he is shipped from one foster home to another. Everything changes, when...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/alcatraz/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/alcatraz/</guid>
        
        <category>Alcatraz vs. the Evil Librarians</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Brandon Sanderson</category>
        
        <category>Hayley Lazo</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cyberpunk Girls</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Cyberpunk Girls” to zbiór opowiadań cyberpunkowych, które wyszły spod pióra polskich autorek. Ponieważ ja uwielbiam takie klimaty z radością sięgnęłam po tę pozycję.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Jest to książka idealna na nasze obecne czasy, w których większość z nas siedzi zamknięta w domach z obawy przed szalejącym wszędzie wirusem i próbuje jakoś zorganizować sobie życie bez zwyczajowej socjalizacji z innymi. Autorki prawdopodobnie wyszły od tej właśnie sytuacji i zadały to jakże istotne pytanie, co by było, gdyby? Gdyby wirus nigdy tak naprawdę nie został opanowany? Gdyby już nie było powrotu do dawnego stylu życia?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Każde z opowiadań jest wariacją na temat życia w...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/cyberpunkgirls/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/cyberpunkgirls/</guid>
        
        <category>Cyberpunk Girls</category>
        
        <category>Uroboros</category>
        
        <category>zbiór opowiadań</category>
        
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rhythm of War - full review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Rhythm of War” is the fourth book in the “Stormlight Archive” series – an epic fantasy series by Brandon Sanderson. It was my most anticipated book to read this year and when I finally read it, I was not disappointed.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As I’ve already wrote in my initial review after reading first part of the book, the author is getting us right back to Roshar, serving us chapters full of action, daring pursuits, duels, and engineering wonders. After that, the action slows a bit, but the situation is getting far more serious and dangerous for all the characters.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In this book...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/rhythmofwar2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/rhythmofwar2/</guid>
        
        <category>Rhythm of War</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>The Stormlight Archive</category>
        
        <category>Gollancz</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Poison River Legend of the Five Rings A Daidoji Shin Mystery</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Poison River: Legend of the Five Rings: A Daidoji Shin Mystery” by Joshua Reynolds is a novel from a fictional world created for a card game “Legend of the Five Rings” (L5R). It was the second novel from this universe that I’ve read, and although it had a different vibe than “Curse of Honor”, I enjoyed it as well.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This time we the author takes us to a very peculiar location – the City of the Rich Frog. It is unique because it doesn’t belong to any of the great clans exclusively. Three of them – Lion, Unicorn and Dragon...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/poisonriver/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/poisonriver/</guid>
        
        <category>Poison River</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Legend of the Five Ring</category>
        
        <category>A Daidoji Shin Mystery</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Płacz</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Płacz” Marty Kisiel to trzeci tom “Cyklu Wrocławskiego”. Ponownie spotykamy tu grono naszych ulubionych bohaterów, wszystkie trzy panny, Stern oraz siostry Bolesne. Powieść zaczyna się dość niewinnie. Po wydarzeniach z “Toń” drogi przyjaciół się rozeszły i wszyscy zgodnie udają, że to normalne. Dopiero wołanie z zaświatów mobilizuje postaci to ponownego połączenia sił.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Cała akcja rozgrywa się w Górach Sowich, miejscu pełnym legend, tajemnic i niewyjaśnionych zagadek. Autorka bardzo umiejętnie kreowała mistyczną atmosferę przeplatając wątki fantastyczne, jak przeskoki w czasie, z faktycznymi historiami, które miały miejsce w tym regionie. Po przeczytaniu tej książki aż się chce samemu odwiedzić te miejsca i...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/placz/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/placz/</guid>
        
        <category>Płacz</category>
        
        <category>Marta Kisiel</category>
        
        <category>Cykl Wrocławski</category>
        
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rhythm of War</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Rhythm of War” is the fourth book in the most epic fantasy saga “The Stormlight Archive” by Brandon Sanderson. Thanks to Gollancz I’m the part of the UK Blog Tour, celebrating the release of this long-awaited book. I will share my impressions with you after reading the first part of the novel (there are five parts in total, around 1200 pages, so brace yourselves!).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I was waiting for “Rhythm of War” since I finished reading “Oathbringer” back in 2017, so I was beyond excited when the book finally landed in my hands! Like all the other books in the series,...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/rhythmofwar/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/rhythmofwar/</guid>
        
        <category>Rhythm of War</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>The Stormlight Archive</category>
        
        <category>Gollancz</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gdziekolwiek Spojrzysz</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;„Gdziekolwiek Spojrzysz” autorstwa Jakuba Szamałka to ostatni już tom serii „Ukryta Sieć”.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Tym razem akcja powieści zawiązuje się w Żelaznej Górze, gdzie dochodzi do katastrofalnego w skutkach wycieku na terenie kopalni miedzi. Cóż mogło być przyczyną tego wypadku, skoro żadne przeglądy techniczne nie wykazały najmniejszych usterek? I jaki interes ma Amerykańska firma oferując sprzątanie po całym zdarzeniu za przysłowiowy bezcen?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Tymczasem Julita również nie spoczywa na laurach. Wciąż śledząc złoczyńców, na których trop trafiła w pierwszej powieści, odkrywa ich podejrzane zainteresowanie zbiorami bibliotecznymi i inwestycje w generatory tekstu. Jaki związek może to mieć z ich poprzednimi zbrodniami i co takiego...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/gdziekolwiekspojrzysz/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/gdziekolwiekspojrzysz/</guid>
        
        <category>Gdziekolwiek Spojrzysz</category>
        
        <category>Jakub Szamałek</category>
        
        <category>Ukryta Sieć</category>
        
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Left-Handed Booksellers of London</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Left-Handed Booksellers of London” by Garth Nix is a surprising adventure in a slightly alternative London in 1983. The Protagonist, Susan Arkshaw, is searching for her father, and following the small trail leading to one of London’s crime lords. Unfortunately, before she manages to ask him any question, he is turned to a pile of dust by a handsome young man named Merlin. From that moment, Susan discovers a whole new world that has always existed just under the nose of regular people.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;From the very first chapters, the weird things keep popping up at you. I love how...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/booksellers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/booksellers/</guid>
        
        <category>The Left-Handed Booksellers of London</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Garth Nix</category>
        
        <category>Gollancz</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The City of Runes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The City of Runes”, debiutancka powieść Dagmary Drozdowskiej, to pełna przygód opowieść o poszukiwaniach zaginionego skarbu wikingów. Jako ciekawostkę dodam, że autorka została laureatką konkursu Pen to Print Book Challenge Competition. Opowieść przypadła do gustu jurorom na tyle, że nagrodzili Dagmarę wydaniem pełnej wersji powieści. Jest ot bardzo inspirująca historia sukcesu i jeśli jesteście ciekawi szczegółów, możecie bez wahania zagadać autorkę na jej mediach społecznościowych.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Dr Erika Skyberg jest zadowolona ze swojego dotychczasowego życia. Jest kuratorem w Muzeum Wikingów w Oslo i w środowisku zawodowym jest znana jako ekspert w swojej dziedzinie. Jedynym mankamentem jest jej absolutny brak szczęścia w...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/thecityofbones/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thecityofbones/</guid>
        
        <category>The City of Runes</category>
        
        <category>Dagmara Drozdowska</category>
        
        <category>mitologia nordycka</category>
        
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The City of Runes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The City of Runes” by Dragmara Drozdowska is a fast-paced adventure through myths and legends. The book is a debut novel; the author was shortlisted in the Pen to Print Book Challenge Competition. The story captivated the jury, and as an award, the novel was published. This is a truly inspiring success story and if you wish to know more, don’t hesitate to reach to Dagmara on social media.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Dr Erika Skyberg is living her dream life. She is a curator in a Viking museum in Oslo and is well known as an expert in her field. The only downside...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/thecityofrunes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thecityofrunes/</guid>
        
        <category>The City of Runes</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Dagmara Drozdowska</category>
        
        <category>norse mythology</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Paris Library</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Paris Library” by Janet Skeslien Charles is a novel based on the true stories of Parisian librarians during WWII. The most important place here belongs to the books themselves, of course. You’ll find here lots of beautiful quotes for different authors and suitable for every mood.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The author research the history of the American Library in Paris thoroughly, working on old letters memoirs and also talking to the family of those who worked there during WWII. All this effort shows in the book, as we are aware that the characters were real people living their lives in those difficult...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/theparislibrary/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/theparislibrary/</guid>
        
        <category>The Paris Library</category>
        
        <category>Janet Skeslien Charles</category>
        
        <category>historical fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Heart so Fierce and Broken</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“A Heart so Fierce and Broken” written by Brigid Kemmerer is the second book in “Cursebreakers” series. Please be aware that this review will include spoilers to the first book, so if you haven’t read it yet, I suggest leaving this review for later.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Harper succeeded in her impossible task – she has broken the vicious curse that tormented Prince Rhen for as long as he could remember. But unfortunately, there is no happily ever after for them. The kingdom is in extremely poor condition after years of neglect and continuous advances from their ferocious neighbour Syhl Shallow. Even though...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/aheartsofierceandbroken/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/aheartsofierceandbroken/</guid>
        
        <category>A Heart so Fierce and Broken</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Brigid Kemmerer</category>
        
        <category>Cursebreakers</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Curse of Honor - A Legend of the Five Rings Novel</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Curse of Honor - A Legend of the Five Rings Novel” by David Annandale is the first full-size novel placed in the fantastic world of Rokugan, created by Fantasy Flight Games. I wanted to read this book because I’m familiar with the card game (which I play quite often with my husband) and I love this world and its elaborate lore. I have to note I am not a hardcore fan – I haven’t read all released novellas and don’t follow on significant world events that are happening in Rokugan. But even if you don’t know this fandom rest assured...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/curseofhonor/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/curseofhonor/</guid>
        
        <category>Curse of Honor</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>David Annandale</category>
        
        <category>Legend of the Five Rings</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>House of Earth and Blood</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;„House of Earth and Blood” was a long-awaited new novel by Sarah J Maas. This time the author gives us not a young adult, but an urban fantasy for adults. The main difference between this book and popular ACOTAR series is putting action in the modern world. Although we still have Maas’s trademarked Fae race, we also have here loads of other magical and non-magical creatures – angels, demons, shapeshifters, vampires and so on. Alongside magic and special abilities, we also have guns, mobile phones, cars and all other technological gadgets that make life easier. Maas fused best elements of...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/houseofearthandblood/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/houseofearthandblood/</guid>
        
        <category>House of Earth and Blood</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Sarah J. Maas</category>
        
        <category>Crescent City</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Seven Devils</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Seven Devils” is a feminist space opera written by Laura Lam and Elizabeth May. It’s a story about seven outstanding characters that are going against overwhelming odds and trying to stand against tyranny of Tholosian Empire.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Firstly, the world created by the authors is ruthless and unjust. In the present, most of the humans are genetically designed for specific roles. The ruling Tholosian Empire creates the perfect workforce, soldiers, engineers and so on, providing them with genes enhancing brain or physical power, depending on current needs. But creating an ideal human being needs a lot of work and experiments, so...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/sevendevils/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sevendevils/</guid>
        
        <category>Seven Devils</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Laura Lam</category>
        
        <category>Elizabeth May</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Caliban's War</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Caliban’s War “is the second book in “The Expanse” series by James S. A. Corey. The story continues with well known high pace and high stakes action. We start at Ganymede, were a Martian soldier is faced with a monstrous creature, who slaughter the whole platoon of soldiers in seconds. The even triggers long-held hostilities between Mars and Earth, and as a result, the neutral Ganymede suffers from disastrous collateral damage. And amid chaos and panic, a child is taken away from a loving parent.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Holden and the crew of Rocinante are obviously in the middle of everything. While working...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/calibanswar/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/calibanswar/</guid>
        
        <category>Caliban's War</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>James S.A. Corey</category>
        
        <category>The Expanse</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Aurora Burning</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Aurora Burning” by amazing authors duo Jay Kristoff and Amy Kaufman was a book I was waiting for since I finished “Aurora Rising”. I preordered it as soon as it was available and couldn’t wait to have it in my hands finally. Nothing would make me happier than meeting sassy squad 312 and join their adventures once again.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;From the very beginning, the action does not slow down. Facing the looming threat of ancient evil alien race that infiltrated human’s intelligence agency already and are going to devour the whole galaxy is not an easy task. We should also add...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/auroraburning/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/auroraburning/</guid>
        
        <category>Aurora Burning</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Jay Kristoff</category>
        
        <category>Amie Kaufman</category>
        
        <category>The Aurora Cycle</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Loneliest Girl in the Universe</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Loneliest Girl in the Universe” by Lauren James is a story about a girl who is the only surviving crew member on a spaceship, heading to another planet to establish a new colony for humans. Can you even imagine how lonely it must be? And besides, she is only a teenager with not only a spaceship to maintain, but also tasked with raising new civilisation among the stars. But no pressure.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In the beginning, we learn about Romy daily routines. She was born abroad her spaceship, so she doesn’t know anything about regular life on Earth and can only...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/theloneliestgirlintheuniverse/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/theloneliestgirlintheuniverse/</guid>
        
        <category>The Loneliest Girl in the Universe</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Lauren James</category>
        
        <category>YA sci-fi</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Queen of Nothing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Queen of Nothing” is the last novel in “The Folk of the Air” series by Holly Black. If you haven’t read previous books, please do not proceed with this review as it contains spoilers to first two tomes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;After a surprising turn of event in “The Wicked King” Jude Durate finds herself exiled in the mortal world. She is furious, full of hate and self-loathing because she let herself be tricked like that. She doesn’t sit around, though. She quickly made a connection with Folk residing in the human realm and got herself stable income by picking up jobs,...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/thequeenofnothing/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thequeenofnothing/</guid>
        
        <category>The Queen of Nothing</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Holly Black</category>
        
        <category>The Folk of the Air</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
