<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kamila reads</title>
    <description>I'm Kamila and I love books! If you looking for book recommendations you can check out my blog and see what I'm reading!</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 15:25:33 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 15:25:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Invisible Life of Addie LaRue</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Invisible Life of Addie LaRue” is a fantasy novel by V. E. Schwab based on the Faustian bargain theme. Addie LaRue, desperate to escape forced marriage and to live her whole life in a tiny village, pleads for help to whatever god could help her. One of them answers and offers a deal, which she accepts without blinking an eye. But as it usually happens, it’s not precisely what Addie was hoping for. She escapes the life the village planned for her, but the price is that she will forever be forgotten by anyone she meets as soon as...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/tiloal/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/tiloal/</guid>
        
        <category>The Invisible Life of Addie LaRue</category>
        
        <category>V.E. Schwab</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Children of Virtue and Vengeance</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Children of Virtue and Vengeance” is the second book in the “Legacy of Orïsha” trilogy by Tomi Adeyemi. I loved the first book in the series because of all the incredible worldbuilding and amazingly diverse magic system, so I was very excited to dive into the sequel.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The first book in the series left us with a fantastic triumph when Zélie and Amari brought magic back to Orïsha. But, of course, it didn’t play out as they expected. Magic not only returned to oppressed maji but also the nobles with magic ancestry, the ones that had been oppressing them for...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/covav/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/covav/</guid>
        
        <category>Children of Virtue and Vengeance</category>
        
        <category>Tomi Adeyemi</category>
        
        <category>Legacy of Orïsha</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Flower Path</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Flower Path” is book three in “A Daidoji Shin Mystery” series by Josh Reynolds based in the universe of The Legend of the Five Rings. I’m always happy to dive into another adventure with Shin as a protagonist. He is such a fun and complex character to read that each story is a pleasure.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This time the author serves us a classic whodunit tale. The affair starts in Foxfire Theatre, which Shin acquired in the previous book, and the grand opening night is supposed to decide whether this venture would be successful. But the stakes become even higher when...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/theflowerpath/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/theflowerpath/</guid>
        
        <category>The Flower Path</category>
        
        <category>Josh Reynolds</category>
        
        <category>Daidoji Shin mystery</category>
        
        <category>L5R</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Lost Metal</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Lost Metal” is the fourth and the last book in The Mistborn Saga (Era Two) series by Brandon Sanderson. I don’t think the series needs any introduction for the fans, as if you haven’t read any of those books, I suggest you start at the beginning. That said, this review might have some minor spoilers for previous books (as it would be impossible to avoid them, as the world in Era Two is a direct consequence of the end of Era One). There will be no spoilers for “The Lost Metal”, so if you are up to date with...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/thelostmetal/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thelostmetal/</guid>
        
        <category>The Lost Metal</category>
        
        <category>Brandon Sanderson</category>
        
        <category>The Mistborn Saga</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lost Gods</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Lost Gods” by Tim Hardie is the third book in the epic Viking-inspired fantasy saga “The Brotherhood of the Eagle”. I had the pleasure of reading the previous two books, so I was very excited when the author asked if I was up to review the next instalment.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What I love about this series the most is the complex worldbuilding. The world is enormous, and there are so many clans and factions that it was hard to wrap your head around it initially. But once you get into it, it becomes fascinating. Sometimes in books, we see that the side...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/lostgods/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/lostgods/</guid>
        
        <category>Lost Gods</category>
        
        <category>Tim Hardie</category>
        
        <category>The Brotherhood of the Eagle</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>To Chart The Clouds</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;To Chart the Clouds by Evan Dicken is a novel from the Legend of the Five Rings world. The main character is Miya Isami, a young cartography clerk. I was immediately intrigued by that theme because I find cartography fascinating, and it’s not often we can see it as a profession described at length in novels. The author studied the development of cartography in non-western societies (specifically Japan), and his vast knowledge of the topic shows in the story right from the first pages. It was so different from, for example, Shadow and Bone, where the protagonist’s (Alina) job was...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/tocharttheclouds/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/tocharttheclouds/</guid>
        
        <category>To Chart The Clouds</category>
        
        <category>Evan Dicken</category>
        
        <category>The Legend of the Five Rings</category>
        
        <category>L5R</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Shadowed by Moonlight</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Shadowed by Moonlight” by Kryssa Stevenson is a fantasy novel based on Pacific Islands folklore. The first time I stumbled upon this story was on Wattpad, where I read a couple of chapters and was so enchanted with it that I reached out to the author immediately to tell her how awesome this book sounds. A couple of weeks later, I learned that Kryssa is working hard to self-publish her book. She contacted me to ask if I wanted to review the book’s ARC. I didn’t have to be asked twice!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What first caught my eye was the setting. I...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/shadowedbymoonlight/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/shadowedbymoonlight/</guid>
        
        <category>Shadowed by Moonlight</category>
        
        <category>Kryssa Stevenson</category>
        
        <category>Pacific Islands</category>
        
        <category>Fantasy</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Horizon Zero Dawn Vol. 2 Liberation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The second volume of Horizon comic, “Liberation”, features Aloy’s other beloved companion – Erend. He’s a kind of goofy friend with a big hammer and a huge heart that is very easy to like. I always found conversations with him funny.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Once again, we’re getting a different story from what we know from the game. Erend and Aloy are on the hunt for a man involved in Oseram’s sister’s death. While they pursue their prey, Erend tells a story of Meridian’s liberation, Ersa’s role in it, and what eventually led to her death. Part of this tale was mentioned in...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/horizon2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/horizon2/</guid>
        
        <category>Horizon Zero Dawn Liberation</category>
        
        <category>Guerrilla Games</category>
        
        <category>Horizon Forbidden West</category>
        
        <category>Titan Comics</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Horizon Zero Dawn Vol. 1 The Sunhawk</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I come to you with something different – a comic review. I usually only write reviews for books, but when I saw that Titan Comics was looking for reviewers for the Horizon Zero Down comics, I couldn’t resist. I’m a massive fan of this series, and it’s one of my favourite games, so picking up those comics was an obvious choice.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Horizon Zero Dawn is an action role-playing game developed by Guerrilla Games and published in 2017. Its sequel, Horizon Forbidden West, came out in February this year. The setting is a post-apocalyptic world, where dangerous animal-like machines rule...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/horizon1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/horizon1/</guid>
        
        <category>Horizon Zero Dawn The Sunhawk</category>
        
        <category>Guerrilla Games</category>
        
        <category>Horizon Forbidden West</category>
        
        <category>Titan Comics</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Efekt Pandy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Efekt Pandy” autorstwa Marty Kisiel to kolejna część komedii kryminalnej “Dywan z Wkładką”. Po wielce emocjonujących morderczych intrygach Teresa Trawna miała powrócić do spokojnego, może nie bezstresowego, ale z pewnością beztrupowego życia. Ale czy na pewno? Okazuje się, że trup może się człowiekowi przytrafić nawet na relaksacyjnym wypadzie to SPA!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Po książki Marty Kisiel zawsze sięgam z przyjemnością, gdyż autorka ma poczucie humoru które idealnie trafia w mój gust i nigdy nie zawodzi. Tak też było przypadku “Efektu Pandy”. Już po skończeniu “Dywany z Wkładką” nie mogłam się doczekać kolejnej odsłony przygód Tereski, która jest moją bratnią duszą, przebojowej Miry...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/efektpandy/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/efektpandy/</guid>
        
        <category>Efekt Pandy</category>
        
        <category>Marta Kisiel</category>
        
        <category>Tereska Trawna</category>
        
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Seven Mercies</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Seven Mercies” is the second and last book in the “Seven Devils” series by Laura Lam and Elizabeth May. I instantly liked the title and the connotation behind it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;When the book starts, the characters are in a pickle. After an explosive end of the first book, most of the Novantae resistance is in shambles, and Seven Devils must scramble for their lives and avoid Tholosians soldiers and bounty hunters. But even overwhelming odds could not thwart the rebels’ desire to fight against the tyranny and help people that the empire enslaved.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;All seven characters have their point of view...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/sevenmercies/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sevenmercies/</guid>
        
        <category>Seven Mercies</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Laura Lam, Elizabeth May</category>
        
        <category>Seven Devils</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Outcast</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Outcast” by Louise Carey is the second book in the dystopian sci-fi thriller series “Inscape”. A story picks up a few months after the previous book’s ending. Despite all her hard work in bringing down the corrupted superior, Tanta is relegated to work amongst community guardians. But after an attack on InTech HQ, she is pulled back to the special forces unit to solve the case.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I loved the dystopian world the author created for her story. A few big corporations are the rulers, and you can either work for them or perish out in the wastelands without food, medicine,...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/outcast/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/outcast/</guid>
        
        <category>outcast</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Louise Carey</category>
        
        <category>inscape</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Between Two Worlds</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Between Two Worlds” is a debut historical fiction novel by Cheyenne van Langevelde. Enid, the daughter of the tribe’s chief, is captured by the Romans and shipped off to Rome as a slave. She will have to find a way to cope with her new, very different reality.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;From the beginning, we get the good feeling of being in ancient times, as the novel is skillfully written using archaic pronouns and other words we don’t use anymore. It does take some getting used to (at least for me, as I don’t read historical fiction often), but it certainly has its...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/betweentwoworlds/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/betweentwoworlds/</guid>
        
        <category>Between Two Worlds</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Cheyenne van Langevelde</category>
        
        <category>historical fiction</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Town Called River</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“A Town Called River” by Igor Rendić is an urban fantasy novel with action set in Croatia and based on less popular Slavic mythology. It’s sort of The Witcher meeting friendly neighbourhood Spiderman in our modern world.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Paul is returning to Croatia after so many years that he hardly even speaks his native tongue. He wanted to wrap up everything quickly – listen to the testament of his late grandmother and deal with whatever she left behind – and then move on with his life. Unfortunately for him, Lena had particular plans for her favourite grandson. When Paul finally arrives...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/atowncalledriver/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/atowncalledriver/</guid>
        
        <category>A Town Called River</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Igor Rendić</category>
        
        <category>Urban Fantasy</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cytonic</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Cytonic” by Brandon Sanderson is the third book in YA Space Opera series “Skyward”. The review includes spoilers to the first two books, so if you haven’t read them yet, please skip it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The book starts with an immediate tense scene, where Spensa is trying to escape from Superiority’s soldiers chasing her. But instead of hyperjump straight home to Detritus, she chooses to venture into the nowhere to learn more about the delvers to gain an advantage in the upcoming conflict. In short, once again, we get a whole new world to discover.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I missed Spensa and M-Bot’s banter. It’s...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/cytonic/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/cytonic/</guid>
        
        <category>Cytonic</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Brandon Sanderson</category>
        
        <category>Skyward</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Empire of the Vampire</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Empire of the Vampire” by Jay Kristoff is the first book in the new series with the same title. The story is very dark and was meant to bring the image of vampires from the romanticised eternal creatures promoted by pop culture back to the bloodsucking monsters of legends from the olden days. And I say the author did a marvellous job.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;At the very start of the book, we meet Gabriel de León, the last Silversaint of a holy brotherhood imprisoned by his mortal enemies – the vampires. He is forced to tell his own story to the empress...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/eotv/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/eotv/</guid>
        
        <category>Empire of the Vampire</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Jay Kristoff</category>
        
        <category>dark fantasy</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Vow so Bold and Deadly</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“A Vow so Bold and Deadly” is the third and last book in the “Cursebreakers” series. I enjoyed the story so far, and I was curious how this tale would end. Word of advice before you read – this review will contain spoilers to previous books, so if you haven’t read them yet, I strongly recommend doing that before reading this review.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;“A Heart so Fierce and Broken” has left us in a very precarious situation. Syl Shallow, with Lia Mara as a new Queen and Grey at her side, gave Emberfall an ultimatum of sixty days to surrender before...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/avowsoboldanddeadly/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/avowsoboldanddeadly/</guid>
        
        <category>A Vow so Bold and Deadly</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Brigid Kemmerer</category>
        
        <category>Cursebreakers</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nemesis Games</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Nemesis Games” is the fifth book in “The Expanse” series by James S. A. Corey. And what a book! I think it was one of my favourites so far.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;First, we have chapters from the points of view of all Rocinante crew members, whom I adore, as they highlight the whole series. When they finally reach Tycho station after New Earth, poor Rocinante is wrecked, and the repairs will take good few months. Using the downtime, the crew decides to take care of their personal matters. Funnily enough, all at once, they leave poor Holden alone, setting off in different...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/nemesisgames/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/nemesisgames/</guid>
        
        <category>Nemesis Games</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>James S. A. Corey</category>
        
        <category>The Expanse</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sundered Souls</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;S”undered Souls” is the second book in the Viking inspired epic fantasy series “The Brotherhood of the Eagle” by Tim Hardie. I was lucky enough to receive the ARC from the author and was excited to continue the story of Rothgar and his companions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Unlike “Hall of Bones”, the sequel starts with a lot more tension. The Vorund Clan has seized control of most land in Laskar, crushing all those who refused to bend the knee for self-proclaimed King of the North, Adalrkir Asmarrson. Rothgar joined Johan Jokellsward, and with their newly formed Brotherhood of the Eagle, they fight against...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/sunderedsouls/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/sunderedsouls/</guid>
        
        <category>Sundered Souls</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Tim Hardie</category>
        
        <category>The Brotherhood of the Eagle</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Look of a King</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Look of a King” by Tom Dumbrell is the first book in a medieval-inspired series “Pillars of Piece”. The story is based in an original world where four nations are occupying the main continent. They all live in peace since the treaty was signed eight years before, but unfortunately, harmony will not last much longer, and violence will once again spread through the land.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The tale follows two young men, Augustus, a pampered heir to the throne, who is a selfish prick, and Cyrus, an orphan living in the small village who love telling stories of bravery and chivalry....</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/loak/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/loak/</guid>
        
        <category>The Look of a King</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Tom Dumbrell</category>
        
        <category>Pillars of Peace</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cibola Burn</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Cibola Burn” is the fourth book in the explosive space opera series “The Expanse”. As soon as the intergalactic gate has been open, adventurous settlers move on to brave the unknown and colonise promising new planets. One of such planets is Ilus (or New Terra, depending on who you ask). The Belter’s ship managed to reach it first, and they started building their settlement right away. Even if the planet is similar to Earth, it is still a strange place, and living there is complicated. Things start looking up when the Belters discover a rich deposit of valuable ore. If...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/cibolaburn/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/cibolaburn/</guid>
        
        <category>Cibola Burn</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>James S. A. Corey</category>
        
        <category>The Expanse</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Death's Kiss</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Death’s Kiss” by Joshua Reynolds is the second book in “A Daidoji Shin Mystery” series based in the world from “Legend of the Five Rings”. I enjoyed the first novel in the series and was waiting eagerly to meet with a witty Crane again.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The story starts a few months after the conclusion of the investigation from “Poison River”. Shin is busy rebuilding the Foxfire Theatre, but deep down, he is already bored with his newest undertaking. When a friend from the Unicorn Clan asks him for a favour, he is more than happy to travel into a distant city...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/deathskiss/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/deathskiss/</guid>
        
        <category>Death's Kiss</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>A Daidoji Shin Mystery</category>
        
        <category>Legend of the Five Rings</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Blacktongue Thief</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Blacktongue Thief” by Christopher Buehlman is the author’s debut in the fantasy genre (most published books were horrors). I absolutely adore the cover, so I was thrilled when Gollancz asked me if I would be interested in Blog Tour with this book.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The novel is rather peculiar. After the first few chapters, I was somewhat appalled. The protagonist, Kinch Na Shannack, is a thief from the Takers Guild, and he is also the one that tells us the story. To say he’s unrefined is an understatement. From the beginning, we are bombarded by crude fart jokes and metaphors straight...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/theblacktonguethief/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/theblacktonguethief/</guid>
        
        <category>The Blacktongue Thief</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Christopher Buehlman</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Broken God</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Broken God” is the third book of “The Black Iron Legacy” fantasy series by Gareth Ryder-Hanrahan. This review will contain spoilers to the first two books because I can’t write anything of essence without it, so if you haven’t started this series yet, I advise you to go and read my review of “The Gutter Prayer” first, and then decide if you want to read it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Every book in “The Black Iron Legacy” has a different central theme. “The Gutter Prayer” mainly evolved around a heist and took place in Guerdon, with only minor mentions of what is happening...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/thebrokengod/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thebrokengod/</guid>
        
        <category>The Broken God</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Gareth Ryder-Hanrahan</category>
        
        <category>The Black Iron Legacy</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Marion Lane and the Midnight Murder</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Marion Lane and the Midnight Murder” is a debut novel by T. A. Willberg. It’s a mystery set in 1958 London, but with a bit of a fantasy twist. I absolutely adore the cover, which was the main reason I wanted to read this book.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I love the setting the author created. Marion Lane is an inconspicuous young woman who works in a tiny bookstore called Miss Brickett’s Secondhand Books and Curiosities. But the truth is, that’s only the cover-up for the secret organisation of private investigators, who are helping Londoners with cases, which police cannot or don’t want to...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/marionlane/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/marionlane/</guid>
        
        <category>Marion Lane and the Midnight Murder</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>T. A. Willberg</category>
        
        <category>Marion Lane</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Blade Itself</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Blade Itself” by Joe Abercrombie is the first book in “The First Law” trilogy. We follow the stories of three protagonists, barbarian Logan Ninefingers, nobleman Captain Jezal dan Lutar and Inquisitor Glokta.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The most exciting thing in the book is the characters. All of them should not be very likeable – an infamous barbarian who slaughter countless people, a selfish prick of a nobleman, and a ruthless torturer who hates everyone. And yet, it’s not all they are. The author creates his characters brilliantly, giving them so many different dimensions that we can’t help but be drawn by their...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/thebladeitself/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/thebladeitself/</guid>
        
        <category>The Blade Itself</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Joe Abercrombie</category>
        
        <category>The First Law</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Shadow of the Gods</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“The Shadow of the Gods” by John Gwynne is the first book in a new epic fantasy series, “The Bloodsworn Saga”. If you love Vikings and Norse mythology, it’s a must-read!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The story follows three protagonists: Orka, ex-military living peacefully with her family on the outskirts of civilised lands; Varg No-Sense (absolutely love the nickname!), a former thrall (slave) on a quest for vengeance and last, but not least, Elvar, a brave young woman who decided she will be the only master of her destiny and forge her battle-fame. All of them starts with their separate routes, but very quickly,...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/theshadowofthegods/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/theshadowofthegods/</guid>
        
        <category>The Shadow of the Gods</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>John Gwynne</category>
        
        <category>The Bloodsworn Saga</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Architekci Czyściciele Materii</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Architekci Czyściciele Materii” to psychodeliczny thriller/kryminał z elementami fantastyki autorstwa Kamila Hajduka. Już z opisu widać, że nie jest to książka sztampowa i łatwa do zaszufladkowania gatunkowo. Jest to drugi tom cyklu „Architekci”, jednak autor zapewnia, że znajomość pierwszego tomu nie jest warunkiem koniecznym.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Sam pomysł na wykreowanie świata bardzo mi się podobał. Mamy tutaj Warszawę w klimacie nieco apokaliptycznym – komunikacja miejska (metro) jest wyłączone z ruchu, metropolią wstrząsają trzęsienia ziemi i inne niewyjaśnione zjawiska a ulice świecą pustkami wzmagając poczucie grozy i niepewności. Otóż stolica stała się podwórkiem dla potężnego Architekta, Tadeusza, który gardząc zwykłymi ludźmi, postanowił przejąć...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/architekci/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/architekci/</guid>
        
        <category>Architekci</category>
        
        <category>Kamil Hajduk</category>
        
        <category>Programistapogodzinach</category>
        
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mirrorland</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Mirrorland” by Carole Johnstone is a dark and twisty thriller. Cat lives in Los Angeles since she left her twin sister El over a decade ago, not making any attempts to contact her only family or mend the broken relationship. But when El disappears on her sailboat one day, Cat is forced to go back to Edinburgh and finally face her past.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;When I first started reading “Mirrorland”, I didn’t think I would like it. For one-third of the book, not much is happening. The author beautifully describes the haunting house where Cat spent her childhood. The building is full...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/mirrorland/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/mirrorland/</guid>
        
        <category>Mirrorland</category>
        
        <category>book review</category>
        
        <category>Carole Johnstone</category>
        
        
        <category>review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kości Skryby</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Kości Skryby” to drugi tom serii “Alcatraz kontra Bibliotekarze” autorstwa Brandona Sandersona. I chociaż cykl kierowany jest głównie do młodzieży, to ja osobiście go uwielbiam. Jest lekki, zabawny i zawsze sięgam po niego, kiedy potrzebuję czegoś na poprawę humoru.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;W tej części Alcatraz udaje się śladami Dziadka Smedrego (który znów się spóźnił) do tajemniczej Biblioteki Aleksandryjskiej. To jedno z najniebezpieczniejszych miejsc na ziemi, a sprawujący w niej władzę Bibliotekarze to nie zwyczajne wredne typy z pistoletami, jakich poznaliśmy w poprzedniej książce. O nie, Kuratorzy są dużo bardziej podstępni i niebezpieczni. Czy wspominałam już, że są nieumarłymi i mogę wyssać Waszą...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/scrivenersbnes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/scrivenersbnes/</guid>
        
        <category>Kości Skryby</category>
        
        <category>Brandon Sanderson</category>
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
        <category>Alcatraz kontra Bibliotekarze</category>
        
        
        <category>recenzja</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
